字幕翻译制作: jifanzimu@tuta.io 欢迎交流
梦想情景
爸爸 爸爸
Dad, Dad.
没关系 亲爱的
It's okay, sweetie.
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸 帮帮我！
Dad, Dad. Dad, help me!
爸爸 请帮帮我！
Dad, please help me!
请帮助我 拜托！
Please help me, please!
而且 嗯 我想...
And, um, I guess...
是啊 然后我就醒了
Yeah, and then I woke up.
为什么我什么都没做？
Why didn't I do anything?
我不知道
I don't know.
现在好像是第三次了
It's like the third time now.
为什么我总是站在那里？
Why am I always just standing there?
保罗 不要让她对自己的梦想感到内疚
Don't make her feel guilty about her dreams, Paul.
你不这么看我 对吧？
You don't see me that way, right?
现实生活中 你不认为我会这样
That's not how you think I'd react in real life.
如果我漂浮着呢？
If I was floating?
还记得那次你差点被淹死吗
Do you remember that time you almost drowned?
当时我反应多快
How fast I reacted.
她那时四岁
She was four.
我记得你告诉过我这件事
I remember you telling me about it.
- 再见  - 汉娜！
- Bye. - Hannah!
记住今晚你必须和苏菲呆在家里
Remember you have to stay home with Sophie tonight.
不 那是明天晚上
No, that's tomorrow night.
不 今晚有演出 总是今晚
No, the play is tonight. It was always tonight.
真的 她不能一个人呆几个小时吗
Really, she can't be alone for, like, a few hours?
我不介意
I don't mind.
你已经同意了这一点
You already agreed to this.
好的 再见
Okay, fine. Bye.
那么 我们在那里碰面 还是…
So, should I just meet you there, or...
是的 可能是
Yeah, probably.
我不确定希拉要花多长时间 所以...
I'm not sure how long it'll take with Sheila, so...
- 你紧张吗  - 不 不是的
- Are you nervous? - No, not really.
我...我想这会很好
I... I think it'll be good.
我想她会明白的
I think she'll understand,
希望道歉就这样了
hopefully apologize and that'll be that.
你能记录下来吗
Can you record it?
- 你是认真的？ - 是的
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
只是手机上的音频
Just the audio on your phone.
我想听听她的反应
I want to hear how she reacts.
哇
Wow.
如此记仇 珍妮特
So vindictive, Janet.
是的 我会考虑一下
Yeah, I'll think about it.
但你该走了 你要迟到了
But you should go, you're gonna be late.
不 我会没事的
No, I'll be fine.
- 祝你一天愉快  - 你也是
- Have a good one. - You, too.
因此 在谈论适应性策略时
So, when talking about adaptive strategies,
为什么斑马看起来是这个样子？
why does the zebra look the way it does?
远在千里之外你都能发现它
You can spot it miles away,
所以不太有效 对吧？
so it's not very functional, right?
有人知道黑白条纹
Any theory on how the black and white stripes
有什么好处吗
could be a benefit?
没有人？
No one?
据我们所知 在与环境的融合方面
From what we know, the camouflage isn't effective
伪装效果并不好
in terms of blending in with the environment.
相反 这是为了融入群体
Rather, it's about blending in with the herd.
你看 掠食者需要识别他们的猎物
You see, predators need to identify their prey.
他们不能攻击整个群体
They can't just attack the whole group.
所以 如果你伸出头来
So, if you stick your head out,
就会让自己成为目标
you make yourself a target.
- 是的  - 那有意义吗
- Yeah. - Does that make sense?
你好 嘿 集中注意力
Hi. Hey, focus.
-事情是这样的吗  - 不 现在不一样了
- Is this how it went? - No, it's different now.
你想与全班同学分享讨论吗
Do you want to share your discussion with the class?
对不起 不
Sorry. No.
好吧 因为你在不该说话的时候说话
Okay, because you just made yourselves a target
让你自己成了目标
by speaking when you weren't supposed to.
你明白这个比喻吗
You get the analogy?
我明白这个比喻
I get the analogy.
好的 所以 相比之下
Okay, good. So, in contrast,
有谁能想到坚持不懈
can anyone think of instances where sticking out
对进化有利的例子吗
can be an evolutionary benefit?
- 你来说  - 交配？
- Yes. - Mating?
交配
Mating.
欢迎来到马德雷
Welcome to Madre.
嗨 我预订了位子 给保罗的
Hi, I have a table, for Paul.
什么？
What?
对不起 我不认识你吗
I'm sorry, don't I know you?
我不知道 你知道吗
I don't know, do you?
是啊 我...
Yeah, I...
好吧 奥斯勒 也许吧 我…我是那里的教授
Well, Osler, maybe. I'm... I'm a professor there.
不 不 我没有去那里
No. No, I didn't go there.
- 你最近来我们这里了吗  - 不
- Have you been with us lately? - No.
是的 哦抱歉 我只是...
Yeah. Okay, sorry. I'm just...
有些似曾相识或...
some major deja vu or...
- 布莱恩 对吧？ - 保罗.
- Brian, right? - Paul.
嗨 保罗
Hi, Paul.
很高兴见到你
It's so nice to see you.
是的 好久不见 希拉
Yeah, it's been too long, Sheila.
我差点没认出你来 哇
I barely recognized you. Wow.
是的？也许是胡子？
Yeah? The beard maybe?
不 是整体 你知道...
No, it's the whole, you know...
那么 你在这待多久？
So, how long are you in town for?
没几天 去探望弟弟
Just a few days, visiting my brother.
你最近怎么样？
How's everything with you?
- 你还在奥斯勒 对吗  - 对我是
- You're still at Osler, right? - Yeah, I am.
我听说你正在发表另一篇论文
And you're publishing another paper, I heard.
是的 我们现在正在做最后的修改
Yeah, we're just doing final revisions now.
所以 …看起来不错
So, it's... it's looking good.
你最终投哪了？哪个期刊？
Where'd you end up? Which publication?
你想... 我们要看一下菜单吗
Do you want to... Should we look at the menu?
是的 哪一本期刊呢？
Yeah. Which publication, though?
自然
Nature.
自然？
Nature?
是的 我们对此感到高兴
Yeah. We're happy about that.
我是说 已经有一段时间了 所以 是的
I mean, it's been a while, so, yeah.
你为什么不联系我？
Why haven't you contacted me?
-什么？ - 为什么你不来找我？
- What? - - Why am I not being credited?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
拜托 群体智能？
Come on, swarm intelligence?
蚁群算法？
Ant colony algorithms?
是的
Yeah.
听起来和我现在的研究非常相似
Sounds awfully similar to my research now.
嗯 我...你是说在研究生院的时候吗
Well, I... Do you mean from grad school?
是的 你当时根本就
Yes. You weren't even interested
对网络不感兴趣
in networks back then.
你的研究都与衰老有关
You were all about senescence.
是的 我...我是说 过去30年
Yes, I... I... I mean, I've expanded my interests
我拓展了兴趣
over the last 30 years.
你用了“蚁群智能”吗 你知道那是我发明的 对吧？
Are you using "antelligence"? You know I coined that, right?
我没有使用“蚁群智能”
I'm not using "antelligence."
看吧 谈论一个想法和实现一个想法
Look, there's a big difference between talking about an idea
有很大的区别
and actually doing all the work.
不不 我一直在工作 我写了一本书
No, no, I've been working. I've got a book.
你有出版商吗
Do you have a publisher?
好吧 我…我想在出版之前写完
Well, I... I want to finish it before I take it out.
我不想被任何类型的
I don't want to be influenced by
合作协议影响到我
any sort of corporate agenda.
- 我能看一下草稿吗 或者...  - 为什么？
- Can I read a draft, or... - Why?
- 你需要更多文献资料吗  - 得了 保罗
- Do you need more material? - Come on, Paul.
我们都是成年人了
Let's be adults here.
你还有多久写完？
How far along are you?
好吧 我还没有真正坐下来开始
Well, I haven't really started the actual sitting down
写其中的一部分 但是...
and writing portion of it yet, but...
所以 这毁了我的一切 希拉
So, this kind of ruins everything for me, Sheila.
这只是一笔完整的拨款 我是说...
It's just a complete appropriation. I mean...
你至少可以相信我吗
Can you at least just credit me?
保罗 当一名教授并没有什么错
There's nothing wrong with just being a professor, Paul.
你也不需要成为一名研究员
You don't need to be a researcher, too.
拜托 希拉 我需要这个
Please, Sheila. I need this.
- 保罗.  - 珍
- Paul. - Jan.
- 你好  - 你拿到票了吗
- Hi. - You got the tickets?
是的 怎么样？
Yeah. How'd it go?
什么 你是说希拉？
What, you mean with Sheila?
是的
Yeah.
是的 嗯 是的 你知道 聊技术
Yeah. Well, yeah, you know, it's technical.
我是说 她完全明白我的论点
I mean, she totally saw my argument,
但我们还没有完全解决这个问题
but we didn't fully, you know, resolve it yet.
真的吗 下一步是什么？
Really? So, what's next?
我会弄清楚
I'll figure it out.
好的 那么 她有防御心理吗
Okay. Well, was she defensive?
- 你录下来了吗  - 不 不
- Did you record it? - No, no.
你知道 这感觉有点不道德之类的
It kind of felt, you know, unethical or whatever.
- 你想进去吗  - 是的
- You want to go inside? - Yeah.
保罗.保罗！
Paul. Paul!
我就觉得是你
I thought that was you.
- 克莱尔？ - 是的
- Claire? - Yeah.
嗨 我的上帝
Hi, my God.
很高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
你刚看过这部剧吗
You just saw the play?
呃 是的 当然
Duh, yeah. Of course.
- 这是我的妻子 珍妮特  - 你好
- This is my wife, Janet. - Hi.
- 你好  - 我是克莱尔
- Hi. - I'm Claire.
- 你好 珍妮特  - 你什么时候结婚的？
- Hello, Janet. - When did you get married?
哇 那是 好吧 让我想想...
Wow. That's about, well, let's see...
- 15年了  - 是的 15年前
- 15 years. - Yeah, 15 years ago.
我很高兴遇见你
I'm so glad I ran into you.
最近你经常出现在我的脑海里
You've been on my mind a lot lately.
对不起 你们两个是怎么认识的？
I'm sorry. How do you two know each other?
嗯 克莱尔和我曾经约会过
Well, Claire and I used to date.
是的
Yeah.
狂野吧？
Wild right?
无论如何 最近你一直在我的脑海里
Anyway, you've been on my mind recently.
是的？我…我已经有一段时间没有想你了
Yeah? I... I haven't thought about you in a while.
好吧 挺好的 我想
Okay. Good to know, I guess.
不管怎样 你一直在我脑海里的原因
Anyway, the reason that you've been on my mind
是因为你不断出现在我的梦里
is because you keep popping up in my dreams.
- 真的吗  - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
就像过去几周发生的很多事情一样
Like, a lot in the last few weeks.
太奇怪了
It's so strange.
你什么也不做 你就在那里
You don't do anything. You're just there,
即使这个梦与你完全无关
even if the dream's completely unrelated to you.
就像那天晚上
Like the other night,
我的一个好朋友躺在街上
a good friend of mine was lying in the street,
被车撞了 流血了 死在我怀里了 对吧？
hit by a car, bleeding, dying in my arms, right?
然后…当然 这只是在梦中
And then... this is just in the dream, of course.
突然间
And out of nowhere,
你出现了 就在那闲逛
there you are, just strolling by.
哇 我…嗯 我是说 这太奇怪了
Wow. I'm... Well, I mean, that is so strange.
那么 我什么都不做吗 我…我不帮忙吗
So, I don't intervene at all? I... I don't help out?
你还在这么做吗
You're still doing that?
- 什么？ - 寻找侮辱
- What? - Searching for the insult.
不 你什么也没做 但我并不怪你
No, you don't do anything, but it's not like I blame you.
我只是想说我的治疗师
I was just gonna say that my therapist
建议由我来提议
suggested that I reach out.
也许你和我需要解决一些问题
That maybe you and I need to sort something out,
你知道 潜意识里
you know, subconsciously.
你…你知道他来这里吗
Did... did you know he was here?
不不不 我只是碰巧看到你们
No, no, no, I just happened to see you guys,
这感觉就像是一个征兆 你知道 同步的
which feels like a sign, you know, synchronicity.
好的 好的 是的
Okay. Okay. Yeah.
你觉得我们可以喝杯咖啡什么的吗
Do you think we can grab a coffee or something?
你知道 叙叙旧什么的？
You know, just catch up and stuff?
是的 我们...可以的 当然 为什么不呢？
Yeah, we... we can do that. Sure, why not?
我是说 你知道...
I mean, you know...
我应该保存你的电话号码吗
Should I take your number?
- 好吧 是的  - 好的
- Okay, yeah. - Okay.
把你的电话号码输入那里
Put your number in there.
- 你喜欢这部剧吗  - 是的 是的
- Did you like the play? - I did, yeah. Yeah.
什么 你改姓了？
What, you changed your last name?
是的 我用了她的 我们以为这是...
Yeah, I took hers. We thought it was...
我自己认为这是合适的 我愿意的
I thought it was appropriate. I wanted to.
好的
Right.
你为什么满脸通红？
Why'd you get all red?
好吧 我只是对整个情况感到惊讶
Well, I was just taken aback by the whole situation.
你不会有同样的反应吗
Wouldn't you react the same
如果某个旧男友就这样追问你？
if some old boyfriend just cornered you like that?
我想我不会变成一个口吃的傻瓜
I don't think I'd turn into a stuttering fool.
我不认为我结巴了
I don't think I was stuttering.
她看起来很高兴见到你
She seemed really happy to see you.
嗯 是的 但不是因为…而是因为那些梦
Well, yeah, but not becau... It's because of these dreams.
你为什么要维护她？
Why are you defending her?
你现在就是想跟我吵架吗
Are you just trying to pick a fight with me right now?
不 我只是担心 我不在的时候这个女人
No, I'm just nervous what this woman will do to you
- 会对你做什么  - 对我做什么？
- when I'm not there. - Do to me?
她要对我做什么？
What's she gonna do to me?
骗我？
Jump me?
为什么问她结婚了吗
Why did you ask if she was married?
我是找话题罢了
I was making conversation.
好的 嗯 也许我有点夸张了
Okay. Well, maybe I'm exaggerating a little bit,
但说我一点也不担心 那是在撒谎
but I would be lying if I said I wasn't worried at all.
这话不假
That's fair.
但我只是和她见面喝咖啡 仅此而已
But I'm just meeting her for coffee, that's it.
我爱你
I love you.
你曾经幻想过其他女人吗
Have you ever fantasized about other women?
是的 当然 我有
Yeah, of course, I have.
- 但从没有出轨？ - 天啊 珍妮特
- But never cheated? - My God, Janet.
你真觉得我有那么酷吗
Do you really think I'm that cool?
你认为我能应付
Do you think I could handle
外遇带来的情感负担吗？
the emotional burden of having an affair?
不 不 你说的对
No. No, you're right.
尽量别让你的神经质劫持了你
Just try not to let your neuroticism hijack you.
得了 又开始性别心理学的废话了
Come on. Not the gender psychology bullshit again.
咱俩都知道你擅长神经质
We both know you score high in neuroticism.
那就擅长吧 最好务实一点
It's best to just own it and be pragmatic about it.
是的 好吧 你擅长…“混蛋”
Yeah. Well, you score high in, in... "assholeness."
我…我擅长“混蛋”？
I... I score high in "assholeness"?
是的 所以 就擅长吧 要务实一点
Yeah. So, just own it. Be pragmatic about it.
这样子行吗？
How about this?
当我见她时 我保持严肃正式的态度
I'll keep it very formal when I meet her.
甚至都不会微笑
I won't even smile.
- 她可能会喜欢这样  - 什么？
- She might like that. - What?
- 她可能会喜欢这样  - 不
- She might like that. - No.
是的 就是很...
Yeah, it's just so...
嗯 就是很激烈 你知道吗
Well, it's just so intense, you know?
我通常甚至不记得我的梦
And I usually don't even remember my dreams.
哇 我...我要为了这样闯入
Wow. I... I feel like I want to apologize
你的脑海而道歉
for barging into your head like that.
不 没关系 这很有趣 你知道吗
No, it's okay. It's just funny, you know?
不管怎样 谢谢你来见我
Anyway, thanks for meeting me.
当然
Of course.
嗯 其实有 嗯...
Um, there's actually, um...
我有件事想问你
there's something I want to ask you.
是吗
Yeah?
什么？
What?
如果我写这个可以吗
Would it be okay if I wrote about this?
什么意思？以…什么方式？
What do you mean? In... in what way?
嗯 我为名为《新调查》的杂志撰稿
Well, I write for this magazine called The New Inquiry.
真的吗 你要出版吗
Really? You're publishing?
只是在线的
It's just online.
它更像一个博客 没有人真正读它
It's more like a blog. Nobody really reads it.
你…你写的是什么东西？
What... what sort of stuff do you write about?
主要是心理学 荣格的东西
Mostly psychology. Jungian stuff.
好的
Yeah, okay.
我就知道你会对此嗤之以鼻
I knew you'd scoff at that.
抱歉 我不是故意的
Sorry, I didn't mean to.
怎么 你想写我的事吗
What, you want to write about me?
不 我想写一些关于梦的文章
No, I want to write about the dreams.
关于无意中遇到你 仅此而已
About randomly seeing you, just that.
这只是…从我做的工作来说 非常相符
It's just... it's just very on brand from what I do.
我是说 是哦 如果你不把我描绘成
I mean, yeah, if you don't portray me
就像这个不合格的失败者 就像在你的梦中一样
as this inadequate loser, like in your dreams.
你真的受到了侮辱
You're seriously insulted.
不 当然不 我是在开玩笑
No, of course not. I'm joking.
那么 你觉得可以吗
So, you'd be okay with it?
- 是的 是的 写吧  - 是的
- Yes. Yeah. Go ahead. - Yes.
谢谢 是的
Thank you. Yes.
- 怎么？ - 没 只是...
- What? - No, it's...
只是我妻子怀疑你别有用心
just my wife suspected you had ulterior motives.
比如说？
Like what?
嗯 你对我还有感情
Well, that you still had feelings for me,
你想念我
that you missed me.
等等…真的吗
Wait... really?
真好笑 她为什么要这么说？
That's so funny. Why would she say that?
我...是说 我不知道 我...
I... I mean, I don't know, I...
该死 我必须走了
Shoot, I have to run.
嗯 好的 谢谢你
Um, well, thank you.
- 谢谢你见我 真的  - 当然
- Thanks for doing this, really. - Sure.
我想我会 会在梦中见到你
I guess I'll, I guess I'll see you in my dreams.
是的 当然不是
Yeah, of course not.
谢谢
Thanks.
是他吗
Is it him?
- 肯定是保罗  - 这太奇怪了
- It's Paul for sure. - That's so weird.
我们基本上做了同一个梦
We're basically having the same dream.
我知道 很随机 这只是 就像
I know, it's so random. It's just, like,
保罗 每天晚上都会因为某种原因
Paul, every night for some reason.
- 你好  - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
你们好吗
You guys good?
- 是的 你？ - 是的
- Yeah. You? - Yeah.
让人惊奇
So amazing.
什么？
What?
你有没有梦见过我？
Have you been dreaming about me?
我有没有梦到你？
Have I been dreaming about you?
是的
Yeah.
你是说 我这辈子曾经有过吗
Ever in my life, you mean?
不 最近
No, recently.
我不知道 我不关注类似的事情
I don't know. I don't keep track of things like that.
你有点吓坏我了 这是怎么回事？
You're kind of freaking me out. What's going on?
没什么
Nothing.
咱能把手机收起来
Can we please put our phones away
真正的聊一会吗？
and have a real conversation?
那么 苏菲 今天在学校过得怎么样？
So, how was school today, Sophie?
- 爸爸  - 没关系
- Dad. - It's fine,
我稍后打回去
I'll call them back later.
告诉我你的一天
Tell me about your day.
至少能把铃声关掉吧
Can you turn the sound off at least?
是的 下次我会这样做
Yes, I'll do that next time.
很快就停了
It'll stop soon.
苏菲 你们还没决定吗
Sophie, didn't you guys decide
想扮演这部剧里的
which character you're going to be
- 哪个角色 或者.. - 是的
- for the... for the play or... - Yeah.
我去挂断电话吧
Let me just hang up.
我必须接这个电话
I have to take this.
- 这是不允许的  - 理查德 嗨
- That's not allowed. - Richard, hi.
现在方便吗 你有时间吗
- Is this a good time? You have a minute?
是的 怎么了？
Yeah. What's going on?
那么 我从哪里开始呢？
So, where do I start?
哇 听起来很严重
Wow. It sounds serious.
不 这很有趣
No, it's funny.
你知道有时我会举办晚宴派对 对吧？
You know sometimes I have these dinner parties, right?
是的 这是最终邀请吗
Yeah. Is this finally the invite?
- 不 是我... 刚刚办了一个
- No, it's...I just had one.
好 然后呢？
Okay, and?
所以 我对我丈夫说了很多遍
So, I've told my husband this ad nauseam,
是关于我反复做的一个梦
but it's about a recurring dream I've had,
不是一个特定的梦
or not so much a specific dream
但我一直梦见一个特定的人
but a specific person I keep dreaming about.
他看起来非常普通
He looks perfectly average.
只是个突然出现的路人甲
He's a remarkable nobody that just shows up.
他只是占据了空间，就像一个派对上
He just occupies the space like an awkward guest
没人真正认识的尴尬客人
at a party that no one really knows.
像西德尼这样的吗
You mean like Sydney?
是的
Yeah.
不 我是说...
No, I mean...
我也…我…我也有过这样的经历
I have also... I've... I've also had that experience.
我已经告诉理查德了
I already told Richard about it.
- 我说了 我告诉过你...  - 是的 我有点生气
- I did, I told you... - Yes, and I'm kind of upset,
实话告诉你们
to tell you the truth.
她梦见了另一个男人
She's dreaming about another man.
是的 和你的非常相似 内奥米
Yeah, very similar to yours, Naomi.
除了一点 我梦见的人我们都认识
Except in my case, it's this... this guy that we sort of know.
是理查德的老朋友 保罗
This old friend of Richard's, Paul.
嗯 我们考的是同一所大学
Well, we went to the same university.
其实他并没有那么令人难忘
He's actually not that memorable.
他有点无聊
He's kind of boring.
我…我不明白你们为啥这么喜欢他
I... I don't get why you're so into him.
我不喜欢他
I'm not into him.
那么 他长什么样子呢？
So, what does he look like?
嗯 他确实有点像西德尼
Well, he does actually kind of look like Sydney.
你有照片吗
Do you have a picture?
保罗？
Paul?
我的上帝
My God.
- 保罗.保罗！  - 你好
- Paul. Paul! - Hello.
我的上帝
My God.
- 能听到吗  - 嘿 什么...
- Are you there? - Hey, what...
发生了什么？
what happened?
嘿
Hey.
你在想什么，保罗？
为什么我会梦见你？你是谁？
你是真人吗？
你怎么做到的？
现在有点不想上床了
珍妮特！那里…那里有大约100条消息
Janet! There... there... there's, like, 100 messages on here.
可能因为克莱尔的文章
Probably Claire's article.
一定是链接到了我的个人资料什么的
She must have linked it to my profile or something.
嗨 保罗 你好吗？
我在梦里见过你
我好像认识你
嗨 想采访你一下
有人想采访我
Somebody wants to interview me.
你为什么这么兴奋？
Why are you so excited?
- 为什么？怎么了？ - 这很奇怪 保罗
- Why? What's wrong? - This is strange, Paul.
也许在你做任何激进的事情之前
Maybe you should take a minute and think
你应该花点时间想一想
before you do anything drastic.
为什么是我？我不知道
Why me? I don't know,
我想我很特别
I'm special, I guess.
一名本地男子发现自己处于
An area man has found himself at the center of
一种奇怪的梦境流行病的中心
a strange dream epidemic,
科学家们正在努力搞清原因
which scientists are struggling to make sense of.
所以实际上 我们不知道是什么原因造成的
So we actually don't know what's causing this,
但这有点像梦境版的曼德拉效应
but it's sort of like a dream version of the Mandela effect,
那是指 多个人报告说有相同的错误记忆
which is when multiple people report having the same
却没有任何符合逻辑的解释
false memory without any logical explanation.
现在 有一种东西叫做
Now, then there's something called
- 星体投射 对吗  - 不 妈妈 我不知道
- astral projections, right? - No, Mom, I don't know.
这是一种精神类型的梦境拜访
This is a spiritual type of dream visitation.
从科学角度来说 这当然是值得怀疑的
Scientifically, this is dubious, of course,
- 但已有报道  - 我什么也没做
- but it has been reported. - I didn't do anything.
这...是我的领域中非常有趣的时刻...
It... it's a very interesting time in my field...
在学校解释这件事会很奇怪
This is gonna be so weird to explain at school.
在线民意调查显示 有数千份这一现象的报告
Our online poll shows thousands of reports of the phenomenon.
妈妈 你为什么这么生气？我很好
What are you getting so upset for, Mom? I'm fine.
我现在错过了整个新闻片段
I'm missing the whole segment now.
但我总是倾向于理性地思考
But I'm always inclined to think, rationally,
任何超自然现象
that anything supernatural
必须是社会建构的
has to be socially constructed.
但这个事 即使对我来说也是神秘的
But this one is, mysterious, even for me.
好的 好的 请冷静下来
Okay. Okay. Please calm down.
冷静下来
Calm down.
谢谢
Thank you.
谁是真的来这听亲属选择讲座的？
Who's really here for the lecture on kin selection?
举手
Show of hands.
好的 剩下的人 在我开始演讲之前
Okay, the rest of you, I'll give you five minutes
我给你们五分钟 好吗
before I start the lecture, okay?
有什么事就问我吧
Ask me anything.
是的 就是你
Yes, you?
像病毒那样传播感觉如何？
How does it feel to go viral?
好吧 今年晚些时候 当我们谈到模因时
Well, we can discuss that when we get to memetics
我们再讨论这个
later this year.
- 是的 就是你 - 为什么会发生这事？
- Yes, you? - Why is this happening?
我没有任何线索
I have no clue.
我的猜测能力和你一样
My guess would be as good as yours.
你会像斯蒂芬·科尔伯特那样做吗
Are you gonna do, like, Stephen Colbert or anything?
没有机会
Not a chance.
如果你相信的话 我实际上很享受默默无闻
I actually enjoy my anonymity, if you can believe that.
好的 你！
Okay. You!
我想也许我梦见了你
I think maybe I had a dream about you
但它 就像 超级模糊 就像
but it's, like, super blurry and, like,
我想更好地记住它们
I wanna, like, be better at remembering them.
- 我该怎么做？ - 我并不是这方面的专家
- And, how do I do that? - I'm not really an expert here.
写梦境日记是一项常见的活动
Keeping a dream journal is a common exercise,
但在课堂上看到我还不够吗
but isn't seeing me in class enough?
谁能确定真的梦到了我？
Who's certain they've actually had a dream about me?
好的 让我们探索一下
Okay. Let's explore this.
这可能会让我们发现一些有趣的事
This might get us somewhere interesting.
有谁愿意分享一下梦到的是什么吗
Does anyone want to share the content of their dream?
- 是的 就是你 - 嗯 嗯
- Yes, you? - Well, um.
我在一片森林里
I'm in this forest,
四处闲逛 吃着些奇怪的蘑菇
wandering around, eating these strange mushrooms,
出于某种原因 我穿着全套燕尾服
and I'm in, like, a full tuxedo for some reason.
还有其他人也盛装打扮
And there's other people also dressed up,
但他们都很害怕 就像被恐惧冻结了一样
but they're all scared, like, frozen in fear.
然后我意识到这是因为有一个
And then I realize it's because of this
一个非常高的男人朝我跑来
really tall man running towards me.
藏起来
Hide.
你在跟我讲话吗
Are you talking to me?
是的 保罗 他会杀了我们
Yes, Paul, he'll kill us.
保罗！
Paul!
我从没见过这些
I've never seen these.
真美丽
Beautiful.
不！不！
No! No!
这就是我所记得的一切
And that's all I remember.
有趣
Interesting.
所以 我在看蘑菇
So, I'm looking at the mushrooms
- 而不是帮你？ - 我想 是的
- instead of helping? - I suppose, yeah.
好吧 我们再听听另一个 有人吗
Okay, let's hear another one. Anyone?
好吧 我又一次袖手旁观
Okay, so, I'm just observing again.
但还是有趣
But that's funny.
有趣的一个梦
Interesting one.
还有谁？
Anyone else?
- 就这样结束了？ - 是的
- It ends like that? - Yeah.
就是这样 我能记得的就这么多了
That's, that's all I can remember.
有谁有更原创的吗
Does anyone have a more original one?
也许有我真正在做某事的梦
Maybe one where I'm actually doing something.
没有人？
No one?
好吧 无论如何 让我们听听吧
Okay, well, let's just hear them anyway.
谁是下一个？
Who's next?
爸爸
Dad.
天哪 删掉吧
My God, delete that.
不 还好 我只是发送给凯尔
No, it's fine. I'm just sending it to Kyle.
- 凯尔是谁？ - 塔米的朋友
- Who's Kyle? - Tammy's friend.
出于某种原因 他不相信你是我的父亲
He doesn't believe you're my dad for some reason.
你俩在调情吗
You guys are flirting?
不 呃 他只是在问你的事
No, um, he was just asking about you.
那么 我终于变酷了吗
So, I'm finally cool?
好吧 我觉得不至于
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
你听到了吗 珍妮特？
You hear that, Janet?
她说我现在是一个很酷的爸爸了
She's saying I'm a cool dad now.
我没有…我没有这么说
I didn't... I didn't say that.
今天你能开车送我去学校吗
Can you drive me to school today?
你想让我送？
You want me to?
我想我能做到
I guess I can make it.
- 珍妮特 行吗  - 是的 带她走
- Janet, does that work? - Yeah, take her.
伙计 这太疯狂了
Dude, this is so insane.
比如说 他如何处理这一切？
Like, how's he dealing with all this?
我们甚至不是那种喜欢被关注的人
We're not even the type of people that like attention,
- 你知道？ - 是的
- you know? - Right.
所以说 整件事实在是太离奇了
So, the whole thing is so bizarre.
太怪异了 太离奇了
So bizarre. So bizarre.
我姐姐其实是
My sister is actually, like,
很惊讶我认识你 你知道吗
starstruck that I know you, you know?
她给我发了这篇文章 就像是
She sent me this article and she's like,
“看看这个人 保罗 ”
"Check this guy out, Paul."
我当时想 “那是保罗·马修斯
And I was like, "that's Paul Matthews.
我认识他妻子 ”
"I know his wife."
- 那个好好笑  - 是的 另外 我也在听
- That's so funny. - Yeah. Also, I was listening
喜欢的这个播客
to this podcast that I like.
他们正在谈论保罗
They were talking about Paul.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
他们将保罗与这个古老的互联网迷因联系起来
They were relating Paul to, like, this old internet meme.
然后他们谈论如何 比如
And then they were talking about how, like,
所有迷因都会变成梦
all memes will become dreams
- 或类似的东西  - 那很有意思
- or something like that. - That's interesting.
挺有趣的
It is interesting.
顺便问一下 博物馆进展如何？
How is the museum going, by the way?
- 什么？ - 博物馆
- The what? - The museum.
对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
不 这很好 很好
No, it's good. It's good.
我觉得我们面临一些挑战
I feel like there's a few challenges for us
需要解决 但总体来说进展顺利
to still wrap up, but overall it's going good.
谢谢你的询问
Thanks for asking.
好极了
Great.
我知道这不是我的项目...
I know it's not my project...
...但我很乐意以某种方式参与其中
...but I'd love to be involved somehow.
是的
Yeah.
不 谢谢 我是说 我...
No, thanks. I mean, I...
我觉得我们处于一个非常好的位置
I feel like we're in a pretty good position.
是的 你知道
Yeah. You know,
如果你想别人提供想法或想要一些反馈
just if you want to bounce ideas or want some feedback.
是的 不 是的 我想 是的 是的 是的
Yeah. No. Yeah, I think, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你只是想反馈想法 也许只是…是的
You just want to bounce ideas back and maybe just... yeah.
我以为你不参与那个项目
I thought you weren't on that project.
好吧 我不是 但现在克里斯要我加入
Well, I wasn't, but now Chris wants me on.
嗯 那太好了
Well, that's great.
- 我为你感到高兴  - 谢谢
- I'm happy for you. - Thank you.
我们还收到了理查德著名晚餐派对之一
We also got an invite to one of Richard's famous
的邀请
dinner parties.
- 真的吗 什么时候？ - 5号
- Really? When? - On the 5th.
这么多年过去了 你能相信吗
Can you believe it, after all these years?
我很想拒绝 但我想我们应该走
I was tempted to say no, but I think we should go.
- 嘿 保罗  - 是的？
- Hey, Paul. - Yeah?
你觉得你为什么没有出现在我的梦里？
Why do you suppose you're not showing up in my dreams?
好吧 因为你得到了我本人
Well, because you get the real deal.
如果你两者兼而有之 那就不公平了
It wouldn't be fair if you got both.
- 你嫉妒吗  - 我不知道 我是说
- Are you jealous? - I don't know. I mean,
- 从理性上讲 我不是 但是...  - 那么也许我应该
- rationally, I'm not, but... - Then maybe I should
稍微拜访一下你
give you a little visit.
你想让我做什么？
What would you want me to do?
你想在梦中看到什么？
What would you want to see in your dream?
哇 嗯…我想见你…
Wow. Um... I want to see you...
还记得万圣节你穿着Talking Heads套装时
Remember when you wore that Talking Heads suit
的情景吗？
for Halloween?
是的
Yeah.
有一些关于它的感觉
There was just something about it.
感觉有点怪异又性感
Something kind of weird and sexy.
你应该在某种情况下
You should wear that and save me
穿上它来救我
from, like, some situation.
这就是你的性幻想？
That's your sexual fantasy?
没有限制随你想
Sky's the limit here
你却说要我穿上一套大得滑稽的西装
and you sell it for me wearing a comically large suit.
我不知道 我不擅长承受压力
I don't know, I'm not good under pressure.
赤裸出现 骑在马上 露着大鸡鸡
Just show up naked, on a horse, with a huge penis.
- 这个更好吗  - 谁的大鸡鸡？
- Is that better? - Who has a huge penis?
- 我还是马？ - 你
- Me or the horse? - You.
我要大卫·伯恩的套装
I'm doing the David Byrne suit.
- 已经决定了  - 不 让我考虑一下
- It's been decided. - No, let me think about it.
不不不
No, no, no.
你立刻就说出西装 那就是
You immediately said the suit and that's
- 你想要的  - 好吧
- what you're getting. - Fine.
你认为其他人在梦里
Do you think other people are seeing
看过你赤身裸体吗
you naked in their dreams?
这会让你兴奋吗
Does that turn you on?
它让我兴奋吗
Does it turn me on?
也许有人现在正在梦见我
Maybe somebody's dreaming about me right now.
- 是的  - 也许同时
- Yeah. - Maybe a bunch of people,
有一群人
at the same time.
多少人？
How many?
几百个？也许几千？
Hundreds? Maybe thousands?
你这样真是太不负责任了
That is so irresponsible of you.
我不能接受
I can't accept that.
你打算怎么办？
What are you gonna do about it?
我会确保你留在这儿
I'm gonna make sure you stay right here.
我必须杀了你 保罗
I have to kill you, Paul.
我必须！
I have to!
你在…你在做什么？
What are you... what are you doing?
你是谁？
Who are you?
打电话叫警察
Call the police.
你在我们家做什么？
What are you doing in our house?
- 对不起 对不起  - 出去！
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry. - Get out!
我的上帝
My God.
汉娜 苏菲 退后！
Hannah, Sophie, stay back!
妈妈！妈妈！
Mom! Mom!
- 快想办法！  - 汉娜...
- Do something! - Hannah...
汉娜 带索菲去你的房间 锁上门
Hannah, take Sophie to your room and lock the door.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 放下刀  - 我不能 我必须杀了你
- Put down the knife. - I can't, I have to kill you.
做点什么 保罗！
Do something, Paul!
我必须 我必须
I have to. I have to.
他在我们的卧室...
He's in our bedroom...
我必须杀了你
I have to kill you.
他过去曾有过躁狂发作
He's had manic episodes in the past.
他似乎停止服药了
It seems that he stopped taking his medications.
那么…那么 他会发生什么？
So... so, what's gonna happen to him?
心理评估、上法庭
A psych evaluation, date with the court,
然后由法官做出决定
and then a judge will decide.
那么 他可能被放回来吗
So, he might be back out?
可能服完刑后 是的
After possibly serving a sentence, yes.
你知道 名气可能有一些
You know, fame can come with some
不太理想的副作用
less-than-desirable side effects.
陌生人可能想和你说话
Strangers might want to talk to you,
他们中的一些人可能精神不稳定
some of them might be mentally unstable.
你应该为此做好准备
You should be prepared for that.
我不会拿枪
I'm not getting a gun.
好吧 不一定是说武器
Well, I'm not necessarily talking weapons.
你家里没有警报器
You have no alarm in the house.
你有一个未锁定的入口点
You had an unlocked entry point.
这会让你家易受攻击
That makes you vulnerable.
你可以考虑养一只狗
You could consider a dog.
我们的女儿苏菲过敏
Sophie, our daughter, is allergic.
那么你可能要考虑
Well, then you may want to consider
搬到新房子
moving to a new house.
不要公开你的电话号码和地址
Keep your phone number and address unlisted.
不 我们不会搬家 我是在这所房子里长大的
No, we're not moving, I grew up in this house.
安全摄像头、泰瑟枪
Security cameras, tasers,
加强你的门栓
strengthening your deadbolts,
保护你的窗户、自卫课程
securing your windows, self-defense classes.
看来你在这种情况下很无助
It seems like you were pretty helpless in this situation.
也许我们应该冷静一下
Maybe we should cool this thing off.
你知道 这就是我一开始持怀疑态度的原因
You know, this is why I was skeptical in the first place.
你明确知道会发生这种情况吗
You knew specifically that this would happen?
这种事 保罗 奇怪的后果
This kind of thing, Paul. Strange consequences.
我认为她是对的
I think she's right.
以此当作警告
Take it as a warning.
我真的觉得你在这里玩火
I really feel like you're playing with fire here.
你什么意思 我在做什么？
What do you mean, what am I doing?
上电视 跟着故事一起玩
Going on TV, playing along with the story.
显然 这些对疯子来说就像猫薄荷一样
This thing is clearly working like catnip for lunatics.
一起玩是什么意思？
What do you mean, playing along?
你真的相信人们是
Do you actually believe people are
随机梦到你？
randomly dreaming about you?
你不认为这是因为你突然
You don't think it's because you're popping up
出现在新闻和互联网上？
all over the news and on the internet?
是的 也许这可以解释部分原因
Yeah, maybe that accounts for some of it,
但这并不能真正解释一切
but it doesn't really explain everything.
好吧 你觉得是有神奇的事情发生了吗
Okay, so, you think something magical is happening?
嗯 为什么只有我一个人呢？
Well, why is it just me?
为什么不是你 或者其他任何人呢？
Why not you, or anyone else for that matter?
所以 如果能证明你很特别
So, you believe in metaphysics
你就相信形而上学？
if it proves you're special?
不
No.
我不知道 我还在处理中
I don't know, I'm still processing it.
但那家伙只是个痴心妄想的人
But that guy was just some delusional man
有他自己的疯狂想法
with his own wild ideas.
我认为这种事会重复发生
I don't think that's going to be a recurring event.
但为什么要冒险呢？
But why risk it?
好吧 如果人们知道我是谁 那我就更容易
Well, if people know who I am, it's just easier
踏入这扇大门了
for me to get my foot in the door.
保罗 我们在这里谈论的是哪扇门？
Which door are we talking about here, Paul?
出版商 给我想写的书
A publisher, for the book I want to write.
好的
Okay.
我是不是感觉到了中年危机？
Am I sensing a little midlife crisis here?
得了吧
Come on.
你是他妈的刚买了一辆川崎的人！
You're the one who just bought a fucking Kawasaki!
好的 冷静下来
Okay. Calm down.
- 保罗？ - 嗨 是的
- Paul? - Hi, yes.
嗨 我是莫莉 他们已经在楼上准备好了
Hi, I'm Molly. They're ready for you upstairs.
好极了
Great.
- 什么？ - 这…没什么
- What? - It... it... it's nothing.
不 说吧
No, come on.
在现实生活中见到你真的很奇怪
It's just really weird to see you in real life.
你已经...
You've been...
每晚都不间断
Nonstop every night.
这太疯狂了 伙计
It's crazy, man.
哇 嗯 我希望我表现得好
Wow. Well, I hope I'm behaving.
嗯 不 你不是 一点都不
Well, no, you're not. No, not at all.
保罗在这里
Got Paul here.
- 你来了  - 我来了
- There you are. - Here I am.
保罗.特伦特 嘿
Paul. Trent, hey.
我一直梦想着这次会议
I have been dreaming about this meeting.
- 哦 是的 我也是  - 真的吗
- Aw, yeah, me, too. - Really?
你的意思是指真的做梦吗
You mean literally dreaming?
你知道 我实际上就梦到过这次会议
You know, I've actually had dreams about this very meeting.
我是说 我只是认为它们只是正常的梦
I mean, I just think they were just normal dreams.
不是整体的一部分 我梦中的这个奇怪的人是谁？
Not part of the whole, who's this weird guy in my dreams?
我很奇怪？
I'm weird?
不 我是说 你并不奇怪 不 整件事很奇怪 对吧？
No, I mean, you're not weird. No, the whole thing is weird, right?
我是说 莫莉的梦很疯狂…
I mean, Molly's dreams have been nuts...
- 特伦特！  - 如果你想谈论奇怪的事情
- Trent! - If you wanna talk about weird.
这是我的同事玛丽·威金斯
But this is my colleague, Mary Wiggins.
- 你好  - 嗨 保罗
- Hi. - Hi, Paul.
坐下
Sit down.
- 这里？ - 哪里都行
- Here? - Wherever you want.
是的
Yeah.
你好吗 最近怎么样？
How are you? How's life?
嗯 情况已经大不相同了
Well, things have been pretty different
自从 你知道...自从梦开始
since, you know... since the dreams started.
那有多有趣？
How fun is that?
我是说 我希望我是人们梦到的那个人
I mean, I wish I was the one people were dreaming about.
- 我也是  - 是的
- Me, too. - Yeah.
不 它是…它是某种东西
No, it's... it's something.
嗯 我们…我们很高兴你能来到这里
Well, we're... we're just so excited to have you here.
是的 我们真的很兴奋
Yeah, we're really fired up.
嗯 可能真的是太难受了
Um, it's probably really overwhelming,
没错 走进这样的房间
right, to walk into a room like this.
就像 “这些人是谁？
It's like, "Who are these people?
我在这是要干嘛？”
What am I doing here?"
也许我们应该退后一步 谈谈我们所做的事情
Maybe we should back up and just talk about what we do.
是的 是的 所以 我们今年早些时候开始思考
Yeah, yeah, so, we started Thoughts earlier this year,
所以我们是一个相当新的机构
so we're a pretty new agency.
我们主要关注在线
And we focus mostly online,
像是尝试将品牌整体配对
sort of trying to holistically pair brands
还有更多 可以这么说 非传统的名人
and more, shall we say, unconventional celebrities,
这有道理吗
if that makes sense?
我想你 就在此时此刻
And I think of you, right now, in this moment,
保罗 是世界上最有趣的人
Paul, as the most interesting person in the world.
什么？
What?
我是认真的 我是认真的
I mean it, I mean it.
不 我们不只是抛出观点
No, we don't just throw that around.
不 我们真的不会乱抛观点
No, we really don't throw that around.
我是说 你拥有的优势 保罗
I mean, the advantage that you have, Paul,
你的影响是…不是绑定到
is that your impact is... is not just tied
任何一个社交领域
to any one social arena.
我是说 你不仅仅是在TikTok上出名
I mean, you're not just famous for people on TikTok
又或者在《纽约客》的读者中出名
or for people who read, say, the New Yorker,
当人们睡觉时 你就在他们的脑海里
you're in people's minds when they sleep.
这意味着任何做梦的人
Which means that anyone who's dreaming,
你知道的 都可能是你的观众
you know, could be your audience.
那是多神奇啊？
How amazing is that?
谁能这么说？
Who can say that?
你知道 那样观众够多吧
You know, is that a big enough audience?
是的
Yeah.
所以 你知道 我们一直在集思广益
So, you know, we've been brainstorming
一堆很酷的想法
a bunch of cool ideas
我们想和你谈谈
that we want to talk about with you.
但在我们讨论这些之前
But before we get into any of that,
我们只是好奇你在想什么 你知道
we were just kind of curious what you're thinking, you know,
你想去哪里 你想实现什么目标？
where do you wanna go, what do you want to achieve?
- 你的梦想是什么？ - 你的梦想是什么？
- What are your dreams? - What are yourdreams?
嗯 我一直想写一本书
Well, I've been meaning to write a book
已经有几年了
for a few years now.
只是一直没找到时间 所以...
Just never found the time, so...
好吧 那么 你是作家吗
Okay, so, you're a writer?
棒极了
That's awesome.
你知道 我们...我们讨论过出售
You know, we... we talked about selling
你对电影公司的真人故事改编权
your life rights to a movie studio, actually.
鉴于这件事的热门程度
Because with all the buzz around this,
我认为可能达成六位数的交易
I think we could probably get a six-figure deal.
这只是真人故事改编权
And that's just life rights.
- 真的吗  - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真人故事改编权？ - 是的
- Life rights? - Yeah.
你的真人故事改编权
The rights to your life.
无论如何 这里有一个很酷的地方
Anyway, here's somewhere cool
我们认为这可能是一个很好的起点
that we thought might be a good place to start.
雪碧
Sprite.
- 雪碧？ - 是的
- Sprite? - Yeah.
是的 他们…他们希望由我们经营社交活动
Yeah. They... they want us to run their social.
我想他们那边一定有人疯了...
I think somebody over there must have lost their minds
或什么的 但他们确实...
or something, but they're down
变得很奇怪
to go pretty weird with it.
所以 我们认为这会很有趣
So, we thought it could be fun
如果他们喜欢在推特上发布你的新照片
if maybe they, like, Tweet a new photo of you
每天晚上都拿着一个易拉罐 你懂得
every night holding a can, you know,
加上一个有趣的小标题
with a fun little caption,
只是为了真正体现这种联系
just to really manifest that connection
并希望改变这种现象
in people's minds and to hopefully alter
至少是暂时的
the phenomenon, at least temporarily,
让人们梦见你和产品在一起
to make people dream about you and the product together.
那该多神奇啊 对吧？
How amazing would that be, right?
如果我们无法实现这个
And if we couldn't figure that out,
我们总可以说它确实有效吧
we could always just suggest that it did work
我们可以围绕它编故事
and we could build stories around that.
是的 绝对地
Yeah. Absolutely.
我是说 如果我们完全失败了 那么...
I mean, if we fail altogether, then we...
这也是一件有趣的事
that's kind of a fun story, too.
你知道 就像 我们试图让人们
You know, like, we tried to make people dream
梦到雪碧 但不起作用
about Sprite and it didn't work.
- 我是说 太愚蠢了...  - 我喜欢
- I mean, it's so dumb... - I love that.
...这有点酷 你知道 有点管用
...that it's kind of cool, you know, it kind of works.
- 我可以...  - 是的
- Can I just... - Yeah.
我们可以回到书上吗
Can we go back to the book?
- 什么书？ - 我的书
- What book? - My book.
我想写的书？
The book I wanna write?
我只是想澄清一下
I just want to make it clear
我其实并不想要这个事情
that I actually don't want this whole phenomenon
成为我出名的原因
to be what I'm known for.
我不希望在我的维基百科上
I don't want that to be the main thing
这个事是主要内容 你知道吗
on my Wikipedia, you know?
好的 那么 你在想什么？
Okay. So, what are you thinking?
嗯 我是一名进化生物学家
Well, I'm an evolutionary biologist.
这就是我毕生奉献的事业
That's what I've dedicated my life to.
所以 无论我们做什么 我都希望
So, whatever we do, I want it to be related
它与我的学位相关
to my doctorate.
哇 哇 好的 看吧 我...
Wow. Wow. Okay. See, I...
我根本不知道这件事
I didn't know about that at all.
嗯 你因梦而出名 对吧？
Well, you're famous for the dreams, right?
我是说 这就是…人们感兴趣的原因
I mean, that's... that's why anyone's interested.
所以 把你联系到完全不同领域
So, it might be a bit of a stretch
可能会有点牵强
to get you into a totally different space.
是的
Yeah.
我是终身教授 已经属于这领域了
I'm a tenured professor. I'm already inthe space.
嗯 你知道 只是为了给我们个提示
Well, you know, just to give us a point of contact
关于我们正在谈论的内容
as to what we're talking about,
在你的领域里
who are some of the big names that you like
- 你喜欢哪些大咖？ - 是的
- in that space? - Yeah.
嗯 有很多 罗伯特·萨波尔斯基
Well, there's a bunch, Robert Sapolsky.
他的职业生涯非常令人钦佩
His career has been pretty admirable.
他是 嗯…
Is he, um...
不 实际上我对他并不熟悉
No, I don't think I'm familiar with him, actually.
也许是赫尔曼·蒂格？
Herman Tig, maybe?
- 谁？ - 赫尔曼·蒂格
- Who? - Herman Tig.
是的 不 我知道这个名字
Yeah. No, I know that name.
- 你知道？ - 是的
- You do? - Yeah.
好吧 我想这些并不是真正的名人
Well, these are not really celebrities, I suppose.
不 这就是重点 我不在乎名誉
No, that's the point, I don't care about fame.
我只是认为这是一个机会
I just see this as an opportunity
为我的工作获得一些认可
to get some recognition for my work.
你知道 一扇门打开另一扇门？
You know, one door opening another door?
是的 不 我明白了
Yeah. No, I get that.
你说的是以观众为中心
You're talking about an audience pivot,
我认为这非常聪明
which I think is very smart.
只是不知道你能否在不出现明显掉粉
I just don't know if you can pivot that hard
的情况下调整重心
right now without a significant drop-off.
我是说 一本关于什么的书 植物？
I mean, a book about what, plants?
是的 好吧 我对雪碧广告不太感兴趣
Yeah, well, I'm not really interested in doing Sprite ads.
不不不 嗯 这只是一个例子 保罗
No, no, no. Well, that's just one example, though, Paul.
我是说 我们有的是创意
I mean, we have a ton of ideas.
那个只是冰山一角
That is just the very tip of the iceberg.
我们有很多创意
We have so many ideas.
嗯 我们的一个创意是
Um, one idea we had was
让奥巴马梦见你
to make Obama dream about you.
这会让你进入一些高雅文化层次
That would get you into some of those high-culture spaces
就像你刚刚提到的
you've been mentioning.
我认识玛丽亚 所以我们可以实现
I know Malia, so we can make it happen.
也许这并不是我真正想要的
Maybe this isn't really what I'm looking for.
我不认为我们双方真的
I don't think we're really speaking
- 在谈同一件事  - 不 保罗
- the same language here. - No, Paul.
如果你有这样的感觉 那我就失败了 好吗
If that's how you're feeling, then I'm failing, okay?
我们可以...我们可以重新开始吗
Can we just can... can... can I... can we start over?
我原以为你们可以帮我找到出版商
I just thought you guys could help me find a publisher.
- 我...我...  - 首先
- I... I... I... - First off,
我想道歉
I would like to apologize.
我之前撒了谎 我从来没有梦到过你
I lied earlier. I never dreamt about you.
只是觉得这会是个有趣的方式
I just thought that would be a fun way
去开启这个会议 好吗
to start the meeting, okay?
但是 我绝对真的是
But what is absolutely true
一直想了很多
is that I have been thinking
关于你的事
about you a lot
我真的觉得我们可以一起
and I just really feel that we're gonna do
做一些非常特别的事
something very special together.
那么就让我们继续谈你的植物书吧
So let's just say we go forward with your plant book.
我从没说过任何关于植物的事情
I never said anything about plants.
不 是你的…关于进化论的书…
No. Your... your book about evolutionary...
- 植物  - 这是关于蚂蚁的
- Plants. - It's about ants.
- 蚂蚁  - 蚂蚁
- Ants. - Ants.
好的 太好了
Okay, great.
好吧 我们继续你那个事
Well, let's say we go forward with that.
我们将帮你搞定那个
We'll help you set that up.
- 真的吗  - 是的 我只是...
- Really? - Yes. I just...
我真的很想和你一起工作 保罗
I really wanna work with you, Paul.
我是说 就像我说的
I mean, like I said,
世界上最有趣的人
most interesting person in the world.
好吧 但不能有广告 也没有雪碧
Okay, but then no ads, no Sprite.
我们专注于这本书
We're focusing on the book.
是的 而且 你知道
Yes, and, you know,
如果你不喜欢雪碧 我们会尊重这一点
if you're not feeling Sprite, we'll respect that.
我只是想请你听听
I would just ask in return that you hear out
我们的理念并保持开放的心态 你知道
our pitches and just keep an open mind, you know,
尤其是像雪碧这样的 因为 你知道
especially with things like Sprite because, you know,
合作大门敞开着…
the door is kind of wide open there...
- 是的  - ...现在
- Yeah. - ...right now.
他们…他们已经准备好了
And they're... they're ready to have
和你进行合作谈话
that conversation with you.
我只想说 现在那扇门关了
And that door closes, I'll just say.
好的
Yeah, okay.
那么 晚上有什么计划吗
So, plans for the night?
不 我要赶很早的航班回去 所以...
No, I've got a really early flight back, so...
如果你想喝一杯 请告诉我
If you want to get a drink, just let me know.
我可以去找你 如果这样更容易的话
I can come near you, if that's easier.
他们从Ace上找到的你 对吧？
They have you at the Ace, right?
他们太棒了
They were so great.
他们真的很内行
They really know their stuff.
他们会给我安排一个出版商
They're gonna set me up with a publisher
并让书印起来
and get the book rolling.
哇 太棒了！
Wow, that's great!
现在你只要写就行了
Now you just have to write it.
嗯 当然咯
Yeah, of course.
那么 他们说什么了？
So, what did they say?
他们称我为现在世界上
They called me the most interesting person
最有趣的人
in the world right now.
噢
Aw.
- 什么？ - 没什么
- What? - No, nothing.
我确信这令人受宠若惊
I'm sure that's very flattering.
不 他们特别说
No, they specifically said
他们不是随口说说的
they didn't just throw that around.
好的
Okay.
我不认为他们是为了取悦我
I don't think they were just saying it
才那么说的 珍妮特
to make me feel good, Janet,
他们已经在跟有合作意向
they're already talking to big clients
的大客户交谈
who want to work with me.
比如说？
Like who?
就像 我是说…嗯 这只是一个例子
Like, I mean... well, and this is just one example,
他们提到了雪碧
but they mentioned Sprite.
雪碧？你要和雪碧合作吗
Sprite? You're gonna work with Sprite?
- 珍妮特  - 我马上到
- Janet. - I'll be right there.
你是谁？
Who's there?
克里斯.
Chris.
我们的截止日期是明天
Our deadline is tomorrow,
所以我们刚刚结束
so we're just here finishing up.
好的
Right.
孩子们在哪里？
Where are the kids?
他们和凯尔出去捣蛋了
They're out trick or treating with Kyle.
凯尔
Kyle.
好的
Okay.
恭喜你 保罗
Yeah, well, congrats, Paul,
那明天见了
I'll see you tomorrow, then.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
他们...他们也谈到了奥巴马
Well, they... they also talked about Obama, too,
也许他会梦见我
like maybe he'll dream about me.
好的
Okay.
我...我是说不只是雪碧
I... I'm just saying it wasn't just Sprite.
你不必给我留下深刻印象 保罗
You don't have to impress me, Paul.
- 我爱你  - 我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
- 好的  - 明天见
- Okay. - See you tomorrow.
好的 再见
Yeah. Bye.
你读过那篇澳大利亚人
Did you read that article about people
梦见倒退的文章吗？
dreaming backward in Australia?
- 没有  - 这是因为 像
- No. - It's 'cause of, like,
引力什么的
the gravitational pull or something.
他们提到了你 所以...
They mentioned you in it, so...
那么 他们是如何梦到中国的呢？
How do they dream in China, then?
上下颠倒？
Upside down?
你当教授多久了？
So, how long have you been a professor?
哇 我想 从96年到现在 大概有20年了吧
Wow. I think, what, about 20 years, since '96.
我是96年出生的
I was born in '96.
麻烦 买单
Check, please!
不 不 我在开玩笑
No, no, I'm kidding.
比如...比如 你对我来说太年轻了
Like... like... like, you're too young for me.
- 你不是结婚了吗  - 不 我不是在暗示...
- Aren't you married? - No, I wasn't implying...
我开玩笑的
It's a joke.
是的 不 我是说 我明白了
Yeah, no, I mean, I get it.
好的
Okay.
但是 我...我结婚了
But yeah, I... I am married.
- 你呢？ - 你怎么样？
- How about you? - No.
我并没有 比如 见什么人什么的
I'm not really, like, seeing anyone or anything.
我现在专注于我的事业
I'm, like, focusing on my career right now.
- 你知道吗  - 我知道
- You know? - Yeah.
你是说做代理？
You mean with the agency?
你很讨厌它 不是吗
You hated it so much, didn't you?
不 只是感觉像是...
No, it's just, it kind of felt like...
像邪教？
Like a cult.
是啊 算是吧
Yeah. Sort of.
我曾试着告诉他们
I mean, I tried telling them, like,
"他是个超级聪明的教授"
"He's a super smart professor.
"就像 他会看穿这些鬼话"
"Like, he's gonna see through the bullshit."
不过老实说 雪碧这事还是挺酷的
But honestly, though, like, the Sprite thing is cool.
- 你应该去做  - 是吗
- You should do it. - Yeah?
- 对  - 我很难想象
- Yeah. - I'm struggling to imagine
任何人看到我的脸 都会立刻想喝雪碧
anyone seeing my face and immediately craving a Sprite.
我会的
I would.
我能问你一件事吗
Can I ask you something?
什么？
Yeah, what?
之前说你的梦的时候
I felt like you implied something
我觉得你在暗示什么
earlier about your dreams.
太尴尬了
It's embarrassing.
怎么 我...我表现得很奇怪吗
What, do I... do I act weird or something?
我不知道该不该说
I don't know if I should say.
好吧 这只是梦 我不会评判
Well, it's just dreams, I won't judge.
你并不能真正决定会发生什么 所以...
You don't really get to decide what happens, so...
嗯 嗯...
Um, well, um...
我们做爱
we fuck.
真的吗
Really?
我做过最强烈的春梦
I have the most intense sex dreams.
通常 我在家 而且很晚了
Usually, I'm, like, home and it's late
我一个人在看电视什么的
and I'm alone and I'm, like, watching TV or something.
然后...
And then...
有人在吗
Is someone there?
你是谁？
Who are you?
谁？
Hello?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
请不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
我湿透了
I'm so wet.
对不起 我好像只喝了一杯酒
I'm sorry, I've had, like, one drink
我 就像 口无遮拦
and I'm, like, no filter.
不 不 没事没事的
No, no, it's fine. It's fine.
不 太生动了 对不起
No, it's so graphic, I'm sorry.
我很高兴你告诉了我
I'm glad you told me.
通常 我听到的是我只是
Usually, what I hear is I'm just
被动地闲逛
passively hanging around.
听到我在做什么 感觉挺好的
It's kind of nice to hear I'm doing something.
我想我很幸运
Well, I guess I'm lucky.
这我就不知道了
Well, I don't know about that.
不 那次太棒了 相信我
No, it's so good. Trust me.
你还想再喝一杯吗 我要再来一杯
Do you want another drink? I need another drink.
- 马提尼 对吧？ - 要脏的
- Martini, right? - Dirty.
可以...可以给我再来个解百纳和...
Can I... can I get another cabernet and...
一杯马提尼 好吗
and one martini, please?
斑马就是这样
And that's the thing with the zebras.
迷彩服是用来混入马群的
The camouflage is for blending in with the herd
因为狮子不能猎杀整群斑马
because the lion can't just hunt the whole group.
它必须确定一个目标 对吗
It has to identify a single target, right?
怎么？
What?
对不起 那些人在盯着我们看
Sorry, but those people are staring at us.
我是说 显然是盯着你
I mean, at you, obviously.
天哪 我们不该在这里
Jesus, should we not be here,
- 也许 我们该...  - 为什么？怎么啦？
- maybe, or should we just... - Why? What's wrong?
不 我是说...我只是...
No, I mean... I just...
如果我要见奥巴马 我可不想听到任何流言蜚语
I don't want any rumors if I'm meeting with Obama.
- 什么意思？ - 不 我是说
- What do you mean? - No, I mean,
我...我不习惯这样
I... I'm not used to this.
- 我们应该 嗯...  - 什么？
- Should we, um... - What?
我怎么也忘不掉 我就像
I can't get it out of my head and I'm, like,
和你在这里 就像 妈的 好吧
here with you and, like, fuck it, okay.
能帮我个忙吗
Can you do me a favor?
这就是我家
Yeah, so, this is me.
很不错 又小又漂亮
It's nice. Small and nice.
是啊 我没有有钱的父母 所以...
Yeah, well, I don't have rich parents, so...
不 这不是讽刺
No, it wasn't a jab.
我是说 这里很舒适
I mean, it's cozy.
你布置很好
You've done a good job.
请坐
Sit down.
- 所以...太疯狂了
- So... - So... This is insane.
你不知道这他妈对我来说有多疯狂
You have no fucking idea how crazy this is to me.
- 我根本不该来这里  - 不 别走
- I shouldn't even be here. - No, don't leave.
我...我想我有点醉了
I... I think I'm a bit drunk.
我也是 留下来吧
Me, too. Just stay.
你刚来 就待一会儿
You just got here, just stay for a second.
那是固定齿轮吗
Is that a fixed gear?
不 是普通的
No, it's, like, a regular one.
那么 我们该怎么做呢？
So, how do we do this?
嗯...
Um...
我觉得我想先改变自己
I feel like I want to change first.
- 很酷吗  - 当然
- Is that cool? - Sure.
好的 两秒钟 Okay.好的 两秒钟
Okay. Okay, two seconds.
一切都好吗
Everything good?
是啊
Yeah.
你想让我去哪儿？
Um, so, where do you want me?
你能脱下外套吗
Could you remove your jacket?
当然
Sure.
好了 现在 你能站在那边的角落吗
Okay, now, would you stand in that corner over there?
- 在那边？ - 在那边？
- Over there? - Yeah.
靠墙站好
Get all the way up against the wall.
- 好吧 那对...  - 抱歉 闭嘴
- Okay, so, did that work for... - Sorry, shut up.
只是...你能不能...再继续一些？
Just... can you just... can you just go on a little more?
只是 你知道 我...我结婚了
Just, you know, I'm... I'm married.
我知道 我们可以随时暂停
I know, we can stop any time you like.
请让我...再等一会儿
Just please let me just... a little longer.
这一次 请不要说话 按梦里的做
This time, please don't speak. Just do the dream.
你是谁？
Who are you?
请不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
抚摸我
Touch me.
什么？
What?
只是...在梦里 你好像...
It's just... in the dreams you, like...
通常都是你带头
you usually take the lead.
是啊
Yeah.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
对不起 只是太紧张了
I'm sorry. It's just nerves.
没事 别担心
It's okay. Don't worry.
- 身体有时...  - 是的 没事
- The body sometimes... - Yeah. It's fine.
从生物学的角度 实际上是非常...
Biologically speaking, it's actually quite...
- 这...没事的 放轻松  - 是... 是健康的
- It's... it's fine. Relax. - It's... it's healthy.
- 好的
- Okay. - Okay.
你刚射了吗
Did you just come?
操
Fuck!
Fuck.
希拉·哈珀的"蚁群智能理论"
改变了我们
理解集体智慧的方式
操
Fuck.
我操！
Yeah, you fuck!
希拉·哈珀的
"蚁群智能理论"
操
Fuck!
教授 怎么了？
Professor, what's going on?
- 我能进来吗  - 为什么？
- Can I come in? - Why?
- 我需要帮助  - 好的
- I need help with something. - Okay.
- 什么？ - 我不想站在这里
- What? - I don't want to stand here
在走廊里解释
in the hallway and explain.
能等等吗 我正忙着呢
Well, can it wait? I'm in the middle of something.
就五分钟
Just five minutes.
我会出来的
I'll come out.
如果我们坐下来会更好
Would be better if we sat down.
怎么...怎么了？
What's... what's going on?
- 这是个错误  - 什么意思？
- That was a mistake. - What do you mean?
刚才发生的事是个错误
What just happened, that was a mistake.
你不该那么做
You shouldn't have done that.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你有时候真他妈蠢
You're just so fucking stupid sometimes.
你知道吗 你以前听说过吗
Do you know that? Have you heard that before?
- 好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
请离开
Please leave.
大家都去哪儿了？
Where is everyone?
我不太确定
I'm not really sure.
- 我很震惊  - 是啊 他们变得更糟了
- I'm shocked. - Yeah, and they got worse.
有些甚至带有性色彩
Some are even sexual in nature,
所以他们现在不喜欢上你的课
so they don't feel comfortable being in your class right now.
天哪 他们做了噩梦
Jesus, they had some bad dreams
现在他们不来上课了？
and now they're not gonna show up for class?
我是说 我们不能就这样接受
I mean, we can't just accept that.
我不知道该怎么办   很明显
I don't know what to do here.  I mean, obviously,
我也必须认真对待学生们的担忧
I have to take the students' concerns seriously, too.
嗯 是的 当然
Well, yes, of course.
但这是不是有点反应过度？
But isn't this a bit of an overreaction?
它们是梦 这不是真的
They're dreams. It's not real.
实际上 我并没有对他们做什么
I'm not actually doing anything to them.
正如我之前所说 这是一个新领域
As I said before, this is new territory.
嗯 我想我需要咨询一下人力资源部门
Um, I think I just need to consult with HR.
布雷特 你是我的朋友
Do you, Brett, as my friend,
而不是以奥斯勒学院院长的身份发言
and not speaking as the Dean of Osler,
我们认为本学期应该暂停
think that we should pause this semester
因为有些学生做恶梦？
because some students are having bad dreams?
我还没有做过这样的梦
Well, I haven't had one of these dreams,
所以我不能说...
so I can't speak to the...
不 不 不 不要说生活经验
No, no, no, don't say lived experience.
但听起来他们确实受到了创伤
But it sounds like they've actually been traumatized.
如今 创伤成为了流行词
Trauma is a trend these days.
这是一个笑话 一切都是创伤
It is a joke. Everything is trauma.
与朋友争吵是一种创伤
Arguing with a friend is trauma,
成绩不好就是创伤
getting bad grades is trauma.
他们需要长大
They need to grow up.
- 理查德 好久不见
- Hi. - Richard, it's been too long.
我们是第一批吗
Are we the first ones?
其实...就我们俩
Actually, it's... it'll just be us.
真的吗 我还以为这是最有名的
Really? I thought this was gonna be one of your famous
聚会之一呢
bring-people-together things.
我们觉得只有我们四个人会好一些
We thought it'd be nicer, just us four.
好吧 再给我们来点酒
Okay, yeah. More wine for us.
- 干杯  - 干杯
- Cheers, guys. - Cheers.
卡洛塔 我听说你现在在一家新诊所了
So, Carlota, I heard you're at a new practice now.
- 是的  - 是吗
- Yeah, I am. - Yeah?
是的
Yes.
顺便说一句 这个太好吃了
This is so good, by the way.
天哪 这些球芽甘蓝太神奇了
My gosh, these Brussels sprouts are amazing.
是的 我们在...
Yeah, we got them at...
雪莉家买的
Shelly's.
所以 我开始觉得 也许尼克·博斯特鲁姆是对的
So, I'm starting to think that maybe Nick Bostrum was right
关于模拟理论
about the simulation theory.
这肯定能解释我的处境
That would sure explain a lot about my situation.
记得尼克吗 卡洛塔
Yeah, remember Nick, Carlota?
瑞典人 牛津大学哲学家
Swedish guy, philosopher at Oxford.
- 他来过这里？ - 来过一两次
- He was here? - Yeah, once or twice.
下次你应该邀请我们俩
You should invite us both next time.
他可能很想和我谈谈
He'd probably love to speak with me.
难道不是我告诉你他的事的吗
Wasn't I even the one who told you about him?
不 我不这么认为
No, I don't think so.
卡洛塔 你还在做陶艺吗
Carlota, are you still doing your pottery?
- 别这么粗暴  - 什么？
- Don't be so rough. - What?
你在拍我的背
You're slamming my back.
- 对不起  - 一切都好吗
- Sorry. - Is... is everything good?
她今天...工作不顺
She had a... a rough day at work today.
所以...
So...
好的
Okay.
不 怎么了？
No. What's the matter?
对不起 我做不到 我做不到
Sorry, can't do this. I can't.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
- 理查德  - 理查德 怎么了？
- Richard. - Richard, what's wrong?
伙计们 我想我们得结束了
Guys, I think we're gonna have to wrap this up.
卡洛塔感觉不舒服
Carlota isn't feeling well.
没有 她生病了吗
No. Is she ill?
呃...是你 保罗
It... It's you, Paul.
她最近做了一些很可怕的噩梦
She's had some pretty brutal nightmares lately.
哇 我简直无法...
Wow. I just couldn't...
我很抱歉 你本可以告诉我们的
I'm so sorry, you could have told us.
我说服她不要取消
I convinced her not to cancel.
我不该那么做
I shouldn't have done that.
不过 我们三个还是应该吃完吧
Well, shouldn't the three of us still finish, though?
- 不 你...你必须离开
- It'd be a waste to just... - No, you... you have to leave.
- 真的吗  - 是的 真的
- Really? - Yeah, really.
你觉得今晚其他人没来是为什么？
Why do you think no one else is here?
认知行为疗法的基本理念
The basic idea with cognitive behavioral therapy
是我们将通过逐步接触
is that we'll go through gradual exposure
我们感到威胁的事物
to what we feel is threatening us
去熟悉它 而不是害怕它
to familiarize with it, instead of fearing it.
杀不死我们的东西会让我们更强大 对吗
What doesn't kill us makes us stronger, right?
我知道你们很多人
I know a lot of you have had
都做过与你们教授有关的噩梦
very upsetting dreams about your professor.
在这些梦境里 保罗·马修斯
These dreams suggest that Paul Matthews
是一个坏人
is a harmful person.
所以 你们的大脑通过
So, your mind is trying to protect you,
制造特定的情绪触发点 来试图保护你
make you safe by creating certain emotional triggers.
促使你避开他
Motivating you to avoid him.
我想化解这些触发因素
I want to defuse those triggers
向你们展示事实上
by showing you that Paul
保罗是一个善良、有爱心的好人
is, in fact, a kind, loving, harmless human being.
好吧 我请保罗进来
Okay. I'm going to invite Paul into the room.
他会走进那扇门
He's gonna step inside that door,
在远远的那边
all the way over there
他会保持安全距离
and he's gonna stay at that safe distance
直到大家都觉得他
until everybody feels comfortable
可以走近为止
to invite him closer.
如果有人感到不安全 请平静地说明
If anyone feels unsafe, calmly state,
"坎迪斯 此时此刻我感到不安全"
"Candice, I do not feel safe in this moment."
大家都明白这一点吗
Does everybody understand that?
是的
Yes.
好了 保罗！保罗
All right. Paul!
怎样 还不错吧？
Okay. That wasn't so bad, was it?
我们让他靠近点
Let's have him step forward.
再靠近一点
Come just a little bit closer.
保罗
Paul.
保罗不会伤害你的
Paul isn't gonna hurt you.
能让他再靠近一点吗
Can we have him come just a little bit closer?
保罗 请走近一点
Paul, step closer, please.
所以...
So...
莉娅 等等
Leah, wait.
看看你都干了些什么...
Look what you did...
嘿！
Hey! Hey!
这是谁干的？
Who did this?
现在告诉我
Tell me now.
（失败者）
别他妈再像个小屁孩了
Stop being little fucking brats.
这他妈是谁干的？
Who the fuck did this?
- 去你妈的 马修斯  - 回家去吧
- Fuck you, Matthews. - Go home!
你为什么不辞职 保罗？
Why don't you just quit, Paul?
- 再见 保罗  - 再见
- Bye, Paul. - Bye.
再见
Bye.
布雷特怎么说？
So, what did Brett say?
就当作一个小假期
See it as a little vacation.
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
我是终身教授 他们基本上
I'm a tenured professor and they're basically
在让学生管理学校
just letting the students run the school.
那么 你还要多久才能工作？
So, how long are you not gonna be working?
此刻我甚至不知道是否还想回去
I don't even know if I want to go back at this point.
我应该全心全意地写这本书
I should just go all in with the book.
你做了什么？为什么一切都变了？
So, like, what did you do? Why did everything change?
- 我什么都没做 汉娜  - 你一定做了什么
- I didn't do anything, Hannah. - You must have done something.
- 我没有 所以...  - 你看过推特吗
- Well, I didn't, so... - Have you seen Twitter?
- 没  - 好像有成千上万的人
- No. - It's like thousands of people
分享噩梦 比如...
sharing nightmares about, like...
- 酷刑和强奸 还有...  - 够了 好吗
- like, torture and rape and... - Enough, okay?
新规则
New rule.
餐桌上不能使用手机
No phones at the table
不要讨论梦境 好吗
and no discussion of the dreams, okay?
我只是说 像 我.我明白...
I'm just saying, like, I... I understand...
好吧 你已经破戒了 汉娜
Okay, you already broke the rule, Hannah.
所以 让我们重新开始吧
So, let's just start over.
不要再在餐桌上提及此事 拜托了
No mention of this at the table ever again, please.
你要把车上的字清理掉吗
Are you gonna clean that stuff off the car?
他们要把我踢出项目？
They're kicking me off the project?
我认为 他们只是想在进入最后阶段时
I think that they just want to be extra careful moving into
格外小心 以防万一
the final stages, just as a precautionary measure.
因为保罗？
Because of Paul?
是啊你知道 我反对取消文化
Yeah. You know, I'm against cancel culture
和所有这些东西 是真的
and all of that stuff, I really am.
但我认为现在最好的办法是
But I think that just right now maybe it would be best
你得保持低调 你知道吗
if you kept a lower profile, you know?
直到整个丑闻风波平息
Just until the whole, like, scandal situation blows over.
这样可以吗
Does that make sense?
他们在学校叫你弗雷迪·克鲁格(《猛鬼街》中的杀人魔)
They call you Freddie Krueger at school.
你知道那是谁吗
Do you know who that is?
我上网搜了下
I Googled it.
是啊 他们只是想逗逗你
Yeah, they're just trying to tease you.
朱利安说你把他绑起来
Julian said that you tied him up
并把他的脚趾切下来吃掉
and cut his toes off and ate them.
你认为我会砍掉别人的脚趾吗
Do you think I would cut someone's toes off?
不
No.
做梦就像是精神病 索菲
Dreaming is like a psychosis, Sophie.
我们的大脑决定在睡觉时开始产生幻觉
Our brain decides to start hallucinating while we sleep.
这是内务管理程序的一部分
It's part of its housekeeping process.
出于某种原因 我们需要这样的事情发生
We need that to happen, for some reason.
但为什么你在梦里那么凶？
But why are you so mean in the dreams?
这是他们的梦 与我无关
It's their dreams. I have nothing to do with it.
你能理解吧？
You understand that, right?
我猜是吧
I guess.
我想我明天会呆在家里
I think I'm going to stay home tomorrow.
所以 如果你需要我做饭什么的...
So, if you need me to cook or something...
- 莫莉是谁？ - 什么？
- Who's Molly? - What?
有个叫莫莉的人给你发过短信？
You have texts from someone named Molly?
她是中介公司的助理
She's the assistant at the agency.
她在打电话
She's setting up a call.
你从没提过她
You never mentioned her.
嘿 我是保罗
Hey, it's Paul.
我...我只是想打个招呼
I... I was just calling to say hi.
好吧 我们可以改天
Okay, we can do it another time.
我只是... 想叙叙旧 是的
I just... just wanted to catch up. Yep.
- 别担心  - 好的 再见
- No worries. - Okay, bye.
再见
Bye-bye.
两秒钟 保罗
Two seconds, Paul.
我只是想让玛丽加入电话
I'm just trying to connect Mary to the call.
没问题
Yeah, no problem.
- 嗨 保罗  - 你是谁？
- Hi, Paul. - Who's this?
我是茉莉 我只是在听
It's Molly, I'm just listening in.
嗨 茉莉 你好吗
Hi, Molly. How are you?
- 喂  - 大家都在吗
- Hello? - Is everybody on?
我在呢 特伦特
I'm here, Trent.
- 嘿 玛丽 你在吗 - 特伦特
- Hey, Mary, you on? - Trent,
抱歉 玛丽刚给我发了短信 她链接错了
sorry, Mary just texted me and she had the wrong link.
噩梦教授的愤怒崩溃
我们要开始吗
Should we just start?
- 嗯 是的  - 喂？
- Um, yeah. - Hello?
- 嘿 你们在这儿啊  - 你们能听到我吗
- Hey, there you are. - Can you guys hear me?
保罗？保罗？
Yeah. Paul?
我听得见 发生什么事了 伙计们？
Yeah, I can hear you. What's going on, guys?
- 好的  - 真是疯狂的一周 对吧？
- Okay, hi. - What a crazy week, right?
很明显 我们得改变策略了
So, obviously, we have to change strategies here
以适应当前形势
to adapt to the current situation.
奥巴马的事还存在吗
Is Obama still a thing?
这可能会有帮助 对吗
That might be helpful now, right?
什么？
What?
奥巴马 你说你们在和奥巴马谈 对吗
Obama, you said you guys were talking to Obama, right?
呃...不再考虑奥巴马了 保罗
I'm... Obama is not an option anymore, Paul.
是的 不 保罗 我们...我们在讨论
Yeah. No. So, Paul, we're... we're talking about
- 180度大转弯  - 我们必须重新思考
- a complete 180. - We have to think fresh.
企业文化不会碰这个的 太冒险了
Corporate culture won't touch this. It's too risky.
是的 但我们得到了来自不同场所的
Yeah, but we are getting positive signals
- 积极信号  - 整个
- from a different venue. - The whole,
我不想说极右
I don't wanna say alt-right,
而是那种反体制的空间
but the kind of anti-establishment space,
你知道 有点像乔丹·彼得森的路线
you know, kind of the Jordan Peterson route.
我们也许可以让你上罗根节目什么的
Yeah, we can maybe get you on Rogan or something.
分享你被取消的经历 就像
Share your experience of being cancelled and just, like,
把这个事转到植物书上
pivot that combo to the plant book.
伙计们 不 我讨厌这个主意
Guys, no. I hate that idea.
为了让我们更好地理解你
So, just so we can understand you better,
你到底反对什么？
what exactly are you opposed to?
我不想成为什么文化战争的人
I don't wanna be some culture war person.
我...我不想引起争议
I... I... I don't want to be controversial.
好吧 好的
Okay. Well, yeah,
这和你现在说的正好相反
this is gonna go right against what you're saying right now.
但我们认为 有一个机会 可以让你
But there is a chance, we think, to get you
参加本周塔克・卡尔森...- 塔克
- on Tucker Carlson this week... - - Tucker.
那里观众很多
So, that's a big audience.
- 好好想想吧  - 现在别回答
- Just think about that. - Don't answer right now.
还有法国 保罗
And then also, there's France, Paul.
不知怎的 那里的人们很喜欢你
For some reason, they love you over there.
即使做恶梦 他们也很喜欢
Even with the nightmares, they love it.
是啊 你在那边建立起了一个粉丝群
Yeah. You're building a fanbase over there.
我是不是可以做一些慈善活动？
Isn't there some type of charity I can do, maybe?
不 你真好  - 但是不行
- No, that's sweet. - But no.
那似乎是在道歉
It might seem apologetic.
- 你好  - 很好 谢谢
- Hi. - It's good, thanks.
- 什么？ - 对不起 先生
- What? - I'm so sorry, sir.
我不想这样做 但有些人
I hate to do this, but there are some people that
看你坐在这里 觉得不太舒服
aren't really that comfortable with the fact that you're here.
- 好的  - 好
- Okay. - Yeah.
好吧 如果他们这么不舒服的话
Well, if they're so uncomfortable,
也许他们应该离开
maybe they should leave.
嗯 是的 但是...
Um, yeah, but...
我只是在享受我的美食
I'm just enjoying my meal.
我什么也没说 什么也没做
I haven't said or done anything.
好吧 我想我可以告诉他们
Right. I mean, I guess I could tell them
- 你即将离开 或者...  - 我为什么要离开？
- you're about to leave, or... - Why should I leave?
我没有违反你的任何规定吧？
I haven't broken any of your rules, have I?
- 我是说 没有  - 对啊
- I mean, no. - Well, great.
- 那就这样吧  - 我想也是
- Then that's that. - Yeah, I guess.
好的
Okay.
嘿 嗨
Hey, hi.
你能帮我们个忙 打包离开吗
Would you do us a favor and just wrap that up?
这里没人喜欢你
Nobody wants you here, man.
我要留下来
Well, I'm staying.
- 你确定吗  - 是的 我会在
- Are you sure about that? - Yeah, I'm going to enjoy
吃完东西之后离开 好吗
my food and leave when I'm done, okay?
好的
Okay.
♪当我知道它即将发生
♪ When I know It will happen soon
♪翌日清晨 蓝色来到我的房间
♪ Early blue come To my room next morning
♪我试着入睡 但行不通
♪ And I'll try to go to sleep But it won't work
♪我得去看看我的朋友们
♪ I'll have to see My friends
♪他们去了哪里
♪ Where they go
♪他们知道什么
♪ What they know
♪我逃走了
♪ And I run away
听着 也许你在这件事上需要更主动一些
Listen, maybe you need to be more proactive about this.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
发表公开声明什么的？
Make a public statement or something?
- 也许你应该道歉  - 我应该道歉？
- Maybe you should apologize. - I should apologize?
看在上帝的份上 看看我的脸吧
Take a look at my face for Christ's sake.
好吧 只是为了让大家别再提你...别再提我们
Well, just to get people off your back... off our backs.
不 太荒谬了 我不会那么做的
No, that's ridiculous. I'm not gonna do that.
不只是你自己 我也差点丢了工作
You're not alone in this. I almost lost my job.
这完全是无理取闹
Which is completely uncalled for.
索菲在学校被人欺负
Sophie is being picked on at school.
汉娜很沮丧
Hannah is depressed.
我们半夜会接到奇怪的电话
We get weird phone calls in the middle of the night.
有人...有人闯进了我们家
Someone... someone broke into our house.
我们就这样让恐怖分子得逞吗
So, we're just gonna let the terrorists win?
谁能保证我道歉后会有什么不同？
Who's to say anything will be different if I do apologize?
所以 基本上 你选择了让我们
So, basically, you're just choosing for us
更加悲惨
to be more miserable.
你...你他妈的能不能别说了？
Would you... would you fucking stop?
嘿！
Hey!
家长们似乎达成了共识
It seems like there's consensus amongst the parents,
如果要求不过分的话
and if it's not too much to ask,
我们希望你这次不要参加
we'd like you to sit this one out.
但是 这样的要求太过分了
But it is, it is too much to ask.
太荒谬了 这是她的重要时刻
It's ridiculous. This is a huge moment for her.
当然 我会去的
Of course, I'm going to be there.
保罗 求你了
Paul, please.
什么？他们要强制流放
What? They're imposing an exile. Am I supposed
- 我就这样接受吗 - 别这么夸张
- to just accept that? - Don't be so dramatic.
我们会找人录下来 好吗
We'll get someone to record it, okay?
你会...你会看到的
You'll... Um, you'll get to see it.
只是当晚不在现场
Just not in the room on the night.
你知道我有博士学位吧？
You're aware that I have a Ph.D., right?
- 是的  - 你呢 本科？
- Yes. - And you, B.A.?
- 硕士  - 我想说的是
- M.A. - What I'm saying is,
我不需要你对教学法发表意见
I don't need your opinions on pedagogy.
好吧 我能理解你想参加
Okay, I understand that you want to be there.
但是...在这一点上 大多数家长都反对
But at... at this point, the majority of the parents don't.
他们担心自己的孩子会感到不安全 这一点显而易见
They're worried their kids will feel unsafe, and obviously,
你知道 这并不是完全没有道理的
that's not, you know, completely unwarranted.
我们何不让大家都好过一点 你就...
Why don't we make it easier on everyone and you just...
你为什么不站在我这边 珍妮特？
Why don't you take my side, Janet?
苏菲不应该只因为你想要
Sophie shouldn't have to be punished
表达一个观点而受到惩罚
just because you want to make a point.
别让我们都吊死在你这棵树上
Don't make us all die on your hill.
你好 很抱歉打扰你
Hi. Sorry to bother you.
写着 "失败者 "的车是你的吗
Do you own that car that says, "Loser"?
是的
Yes.
我该从何说起？
Where do I begin?
我先说这个吧
Let me start with this.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 我之前没有提到这个问题
I'm sorry, I didn't address this earlier.
我向所有经历过可怕噩梦的人
I'm sorry to anyone who's had one of those terrible,
表达歉意
terrible nightmares.
我如此情绪低落的原因
The reason why I'm so emotionally distressed
是因为我自己也做过噩梦了
right now is because I had one myself.
我经历过你们中许多人一定经历过的事...
I've experienced what so many of you must have experienced...
被一名男子暴力袭击和虐待
being violently attacked and abused by a man
那男的长得像我
who looks like me.
我必须强调 那个人不是我
I have to stress, that man is not me.
我现在是根据实际生活经验发言
And I speak now from actual lived experience.
我也是你们中的一员
I'm one of you.
我在生活中饱受诋毁 在梦中被追杀
I've been vilified in my life, haunted in my dreams.
我的存在让人们感到不安
My mere presence upsets people
不是因为我真的做了什么事
and not because I've actually done anything.
而是因为人们想象我做过的事情
But because people imagine I've done things.
我因此受到惩罚 这真的公平吗
Is it really fair that I should be punished for that?
难道我不是这整个事情中最大的受害者吗
Am I not the biggest victim in this whole phenomenon?
看看它是怎么影响我的生活的吧！
Just look at how it's affecting my life!
但就因为人们想象我做过的事
But because people imagine I've done things.
我真的要自杀了
I'm actually gonna have to kill myself.
这样做真的公平吗
Is it really fair that
我应该为此受到惩罚吗
I should be punished for that?
- 他在干什么？ - 难道我不是
- What is he doing? - Am I not the biggest
这整个事情中最大的受害者吗
victim in this whole phenomenon?
操
Fuck.
这完全是毫无诚意和自作多情
It was completely insincere and self-serving.
什么？哪部分？
What? Which part?
所有一切
All of it.
太尴尬了 保罗
It's embarrassing, Paul.
嫁给了你 现在真是丢人
It's embarrassing to be married to you right now.
谢谢你让我留下来
Thanks for letting me stay.
是的 只是提个醒
Yeah. Just a heads up.
我妻子不太喜欢这个主意
My wife's not too hot on the idea,
所以 我想应该是住地下室 如果可以的话
so I think it's gonna be in the basement, if that's okay.
什么味道？
What's the smell?
我想那是丙烷罐
I think that's the propane tank.
我会打开一扇窗
I'll crack open a window.
我...我就不能睡在楼上的沙发上吗
I... I can't just sleep on the couch upstairs?
对不起
I'm sorry, man.
如果你需要什么 给我发短信 我会下来的
If you need anything, just text me, I'll come down.
- 谢谢  - 好的
- Thanks. - Okay.
抱歉 先生
Excuse me. Sir.
我看到了我的女儿 她在舞台上
I'm seeing my daughter. She's on stage.
你是马修斯先生吧？
You're Mr. Matthews, right?
- 不  - 你不是保罗·马修斯？
- No. - You're not Paul Matthews?
不
No.
呼叫保安
Call security.
你不能来这里 保罗
You can't be here, Paul.
让我看看吧 我会在结束前离开的
Let me just watch, I'll leave before it's over.
- 我们已经达成协议了啊  - 别这样
- I thought we had an agreement. - Come on.
我只想看几分钟
I just want to watch for a few minutes.
- 尊重我们的边界  - 这太荒谬了
- Respect our boundaries. - This is ridiculous.
- 让我进去  - 保罗
- Let me in. - Paul!
他袭击了我
He attacked me.
他...保罗·马修斯袭击了我
He... Paul Matthews attacked me!
这是一个意外
It was an accident.
她不让我进去
She wouldn't let me in.
我只想看看我的女儿
I just want to see my daughter.
她不让我进去
She wouldn't let me in.
这是一个意外
It was an accident.
我只想看看我的女儿
I just want to see my daughter.
- 嘿 停下  - 不 那是个意外
- Hey, stop. - No, it was an accident.
那是个意外 索菲 那是个意外
It was an accident. Sophie, it was an accident.
停下
Hold it!
所以...苏菲 这是一个意外
So... Sophie, it was an accident.
放开我 放开我
Get off me! Get off of me!
一个普通人
An average man,
轰动一时的文化事件
a cultural sensation,
梦变成了噩梦
a dream turned into a nightmare.
有一段时间 睡觉意味着
For a period, going to sleep
要冒着被这个人虐待的风险
meant risking abuse from this man.
尽管我们仍然不明白
Though we still don't understand how
这种现象是怎么开始的 为什么会突然停止？
this phenomenon started or why it suddenly stopped,
我们可以放心 在猛烈攻击之后
we can rest assured that after violently attacking
去年秋天 一名中学教师
a middle school teacher last fall,
保罗·马修斯 还有我们所有人的梦
Paul Matthews disappeared from the public eye
都一起从公众视线中消失了
and our collective dreams, all together.
但保罗的遭遇也带来了一线希望
But through the case of Paul came one silver lining,
梦境科学的一场革命
a revolution in dream science.
现在 忘掉噩梦 以积极的方式体验
So now forget the nightmares and experience a positive way
与纪夫的梦幻之旅吧
of dream travel with Norio.
欢迎来到梦想之家
Welcome to the Dream House!
这就是梦想之家
This is the Dream House
在好莱坞山顶上
on top of the Hollywood Hills,
下一件大事正在发生的地方
where the next big thing is happening,
你梦中的广告
ads in your dreams.
"梦想影响者" 或者 "心灵广告商"
"Dreamfluencers," or, like, "mindvertisers."
我觉得还没有正式的名称
I don't think there's like an official title yet.
我认为社交媒体已经结束了
Well, I think social media is over.
比如 如果你能在别人脑海里推广歌曲
Like if you can promote a song or a product actually
或产品 那就更有效果了
in someone's head then that's, like, way more powerful.
如果一个人能进入别人的梦境
If one man could enter other people's dreams,
我们都不能吗
couldn't any of us?
一位科学家开始寻找一种方法
One scientist set out to find a way.
我们必须重新考虑整个领域
We had to rethink the whole field.
意识比我们想象的要复杂得多
Consciousness is more complex than we thought.
二元论是对的 荣格是对的
Dualism was right. Jung was right.
有一种集体潜意识
There is a collective subconscious.
保罗·马修斯证明了这一点 即使是偶然
Paul Matthews proved that, even if accidentally.
如果没有他 诺伊欧肯定不会存在
The Norio would definitely not exist without him.
布莱恩·伯格是"诺里欧"的发明者
Brian Berg is the inventor of the Norio,
一个让梦想旅行成为可能的装置
a device that makes it possible to dream travel.
这就像冥想或催眠
It's like meditation or hypnagogia.
使用神经技术
Using neurotechnology,
诺伊欧能让你在梦中拜访任何人
the Norio allows you to visit anyone in their dreams.
看起来他只是在休息
It may look like he's just resting.
但现在 布莱恩在随机的
But right now, Brian's inside the dream
一个19岁韩国男孩的梦里
of a random 19-year-old boy in South Korea.
让人耳目一新
It's refreshing.
我觉得如果人们对它进行评判
I feel like if people are judging it,
那么他们就不会真正理解
then they don't really understand it.
这并不奇怪
It's not weird.
这就像 我们会在你的梦里
It's just like, we're gonna be in your dream
出现一会儿 我们将展示
for a brief moment. We're gonna showcase
一些商品 或者播放一首热门新歌 说几句话
some merch or play a hot new track and say a few things
然后我们就走 就这样
and then we're out. That's it.
保罗·马修斯让很多人怀疑
Paul Matthews left many skeptical
梦想旅行
about dream travel.
但诺伊欧保证不会发生噩梦
But the Norio has a no-nightmare guarantee.
未经同意
Without enthusiastic consent
梦就会这样结束
the dream will simply be terminated.
我是说 人们总是把保罗·马修斯作为
I mean, people always use Paul Matthews as
警世故事
the cautionary tale.
好吧 没有他 这个行业可能就不存在了
Okay, this industry might not exist without him.
但同时 他也给它打上了负面的印记
But also, he put such a negative stamp on it.
他利用了所有这些力量 这有点疯狂
It's kind of insane that he harnessed all of this power,
只是为了恐吓人们
just so he could terrorize people.-
好的
Okay.
不错
Nice.
好了 姑娘们 想看看卧室吗
Okay, girls, wanna look at the bedrooms
看看你喜欢哪个？
and see which ones you like?
我不喜欢
I don't like it.
请去看看卧室
Go look at the bedrooms, please.
所以 我的朋友真的曾做过那样的梦
So, my friend actually used to have those dreams.
至少她是这么说的
Or so she claimed, at least.
是啊
Ha, yeah.
发生了什么事？比如 就是突然停了还是...
So, what happened? Like, they just stopped or...
我只觉得有一段时间没听说过了
I just feel like I haven't heard of them in a while.
我不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
我猜 人们不再做那些梦了
People stopped having them, I guess.
如果我现在听到什么 大多都是在国外
If I hear anything now, it's mostly abroad.
什么味道？
What's the smell?
有人告诉我 老主人非常喜欢动物
I was told that the old owners were big animal lovers.
我相信味道会很快散掉的
I'm sure it'll air out in time.
在你离开之前
Um, hey, before you leave,
你最近在家里看到克里斯了吗
have you seen that guy Chris around the house lately?
嗯 是啊 嗯 是的
Um, yeah. Yeah.
我想 大概是一周前吧
Maybe, like, a week ago, I think.
- 他经常来这里吗  - 不常来
- Is he here often? - I mean, not really.
他过夜吗
Does he stay over?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
汉娜 他过夜吗
Hannah, does he stay over?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 再见 爸爸  - 再见
- Bye, Dad. - Bye.
- 我爱你  - 爱你
- I love you. - Love you!
我会从法国给你带回来很酷的东西
I'll bring you back something cool from France.
- 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
那地方怎么样？
How was the place?
是啊 你知道 很好
Yeah, you know, it was nice.
- 位置好  - 很好
- Good location. - Good.
我觉得索菲不是很喜欢
I don't think Sophie really liked it.
她一直在问 "你为什么不搬回来和我们一起住？"
She kept asking, "Why don't you just move back in with us?"
是啊
Yeah.
成本方面如何？
And cost-wise, good?
你知道 在定居点之间
You know, between the settlement
有奥斯勒和出书的合同 我应该没问题
from Osler and the book deal, I should be fine.
- 事实上 绰绰有余  - 好 太好了
- More than fine, actually. - Okay, great.
对了 你最近在梦里见过我吗
Have you been seeing me in your dreams lately, by the way?
没有 你为什么一直问？
No. Why do you keep asking?
我只是好奇
I'm just curious.
- 该死 我迟到了  - 你要去哪儿？
- Shit, I'm late. - Where are you going?
我和出版商要开网络会议
Well, I've got a Zoom call with the publisher.
他们正试图延长时间
They're trying to expand the tour.
我可能已经在巴黎待了整整一个月了
I might be a whole month now in Paris.
- 太疯狂了  - 太激动人心了
- It's crazy. - That's exciting.
在你离开之前我是见不到你了 是吗
I guess I won't see you before you leave, then?
我四天后出发 我可以过来看看
I leave in four days. I can swing by.
不用了 等你回来再见吧
No, it's fine. I'll see you when you're back.
好吧 好的
Yeah. Okay.
再见
Bye.
再见 保罗
Bye, Paul.
嘿 保罗
Hey, Paul.
我喜欢你穿这些
I love those on you.
来吧 试试看和我一起跳吧
Hey, come on, try them out. Dance with me.
滚出去
Get out.
- 滚出去  - 不 不 试试跳舞
- Get out! - No, no, try to dance.
请不要打迪伦
Please don't hit Dylan.
因为有了这些 你的拳头会更有力
'Cause your punches will pack more heat with these
来自 Alpha Monster Gains 的超美味酮类补充剂
ultra-yummy keto supplements from Alpha Monster Gains.
操 让我再来一次 对不起
Fuck, let me just take that again. I'm sorry.
有了它们 你的拳头会更有力
Your punches will pack more heat with these
来自 Ultra Yummy 的超美味酮类补充剂...
ultra-yummy keto supplements from Ultra Yummy...
- 妈的  - 等一下
- Fuck. - Wait a minute.
哪里是...
Where's the...
首先是一本名为《Rue Morgue》的杂志
So, first up is a magazine called Rue Morgue.
他们写神话、邪教、恐怖电影 诸如此类的东西
They write about myths, cults, horror movies, stuff like that.
你带书了吗
Did you bring a copy of the book?
不 不 它将直接进入商店
No, no. It's going straight to the stores
我们将在那里看到它
and we'll see it there.
能帮我戴上吗
Can you put it on for me?
还是算了吧
I'd rather not.
不 我只是不想
No, it's just, I don't want to.
你不想吗
You don't want to?
手套很酷 我觉得你应该戴上它
The glove is cool and I think you should wear it.
我能说不吗
Can I say no?
来吧 这是有道理的
Come on. It makes sense.
你是个噩梦 这很酷
You are nightmare guy, it's totally cool.
理清思绪
Clear your mind.
这是最重要的一步
And this is the most important step.
为你的探访设定一个意图
Set an intention for your visitation.
不 它还在商店里
No, it's still at the store.
我想他们只是换了位置什么的
I think they just changed the room or something.
也许他们需要更大的空间
Maybe they needed a bigger space.
要成功进入
To successfully enter
别人的梦里需要大量的练习
someone's dream is gonna require a lot of practice.
拿到诺伊奥只是第一步
Getting the Norio is just the first step.
你好 保罗
Bonjour,Paul.
哇 好多人
Bonjour. Wow, big turnout.
不 那是为另一项活动准备的
No, that is for the other event.
I...I...我很抱歉
I... I... I'm so sorry.
有冲突
There was a conflict.
嗯 他们不得不把你搬到楼下
Um, they had to move you downstairs,
但是 来 来 这边走
but come, come, this way.
瞧就是它了
Voila. This is it.
是那本书吗
Is that the book?
实际上 我还没见过它的实体版
I haven't actually seen a physical copy of it yet.
好的
Okay.
好薄啊
Wow. It's so thin.
一定是翻译得太短了
Must have gotten shorter in translation.
标题也改了？
They changed the title, too?
我是你的噩梦
I Am Your Nightmare.
- 这...这不是标题？ - 不是
- That... that is not the title? - No.
应该是梦中场景
It was supposed to be Dream Scenario.
但这...这也好 我想
But this is... this is fine, I guess.
是啊 这...也行
Yeah, it's... it's fine.
这可能更适合读者口味
It probably works better for the demographic.
我该把它交给谁？
Who do I make it out to?
妈的
Fuck!
妈的妈的
Shit. Fuck.
你还好吗 让
Are you all right? Jean!
妈的 他去哪儿了？让
Fuck, where'd he go? Jean!
妈的
Fuck.
- 大家好 我是利亚姆  - 今天 我将教你们
- Hey guys, it's Liam. - Today, I'll be teaching you
如何用诺伊欧进入别人的梦境
how to enter someone else's dream using the Norio.
把它当成冥想吧
Think of it as a meditation.
闭上眼睛 放松身体
Close your eyes, relax your body,
并全神贯注于你想进入
and hyper-focus on the person whose dream
梦境的那人
you're trying to enter.
尽量选择欢迎你的人
Try to pick someone who welcomes your presence,
否则这整件事
or else this whole thing
几乎是不可能的
will be pretty much impossible.
一旦你锁定了对方
So, once you have your dreamer locked in,
剩下的就交给诺伊欧吧...
the Norio will do the rest...
我希望这是真的
I wish this was real.
♪你站的地方
♪ Here where you are standing
♪恐龙曾跳过舞
♪ The dinosaurs did a dance
♪印第安人曾讲过故事
♪ The Indians told a story
♪现在它已成为过去
♪ Now it has come to pass
♪印第安人有一个传说
♪ The Indians had a legend
♪西班牙人为黄金而生
♪ The Spaniards lived For gold
♪白人来杀了他们
♪ The white man came And killed them
♪但他们并没有真的离开
♪ But they haven't Really gone
♪我们生活在梦幻之城
♪ We live in the city Of dreams
♪我们行驶在火之高速公路上
♪ We drive on The highway of fire
♪我们是否应该醒来
♪ Should we awake
♪发现它不见了
♪ And find it gone
♪记住这里 我们最爱的小镇
♪ Remember this Our favorite town
♪来自德国和欧洲
♪ From Germany and Europe
♪和美国南部
♪ And Southern U.S.A.
♪他们在这里建造了这个小镇
♪ They made this Little town here
♪我们现在住在这里
♪ That we live in to this day
♪白人的孩子们
♪ The children of the white man
♪在电视上看到印第安人
♪ Saw Indians on TV
♪听说了这个传说
♪ And heard about the legend
♪他们的城市是个梦
♪ How their city was a dream
♪我们生活在梦幻之城
♪ We live in the city of dreams
♪我们行驶在火焰的高速公路上
♪ We drive On the highway of fire
♪我们是否应该醒来
♪ Should we awake
♪发现它不见了
♪ And find it gone
♪记住这里 我们最爱的小镇
♪ Remember this Our favorite town
♪内战结束了
♪ The Civil War is over
♪以及第一次和第二次世界大战
♪ And World War One and Two
♪如果我们能住在一起
♪ If we can live together
♪梦想可能会实现
♪ The dream it might come true
♪混凝土下面
♪ Underneath the concrete
♪梦想仍在
♪ The dream is still alive
♪一亿辈子
♪ A hundred million lifetimes
♪一个不死的世界
♪ A world that never dies
♪我们生活在梦幻之城
♪ We live in the city of dreams
♪我们行驶在火焰的高速公路上
♪ We drive On the highway of fire
♪我们是否应该醒来
♪ Should we awake
♪发现它不见了
♪ And find it gone
♪记住我们最爱的小镇
♪ Remember this Our favorite town
♪我们生活在梦幻之城
♪ We live in the city of dreams
♪我们行驶在火焰的高速公路上
♪ We drive On the highway of fire
♪我们是否应该醒来
♪ Should we awake
♪发现它不见了
♪ And find it gone
♪记住这个我们最爱的小镇
♪ Remember this Our favorite town ♪